Monal S: In the meantime, let me just… good morning.
Monal S: How's everyone?
Monal S: Super bad.
Monal S: How's everyone doing?
Monal S: Is it good now?
Monal S: Was this not coming, it is good now? Yes. So, I have also announced in the Notion, I have written in the announcement section, that 4th February, that is Wednesday, is holiday. Alright? So, enjoy your holiday.
Monal S: Take your time. I will not suggest you learn everything whenever you get time. Sometimes you have to give yourself a break.
Monal S: So, give yourself a break, yes. Oh, sorry, 4th March, guys, sorry.
Monal S: 4th March, alright? 4th March is Wednesday.
Monal S: So it's up to you if you want to revise, if you want to enjoy, but sometimes…
Monal S: Having good time is also required.
Monal S: Finally, time to revise, that's great, that's great, guys. Fourth is Wednesday, done. Alright? Happy.
Monal S: So if someone asks in the community, please do help them out that we don't have our classes, alright?
Monal S: Others, how are you guys?
Monal S: Yep, FFC as well. I'm doing good.
Monal S: Yes, probably.
Monal S: You shaved off? Yeah, I was shaved from yesterday.
Monal S: When we don't have classes.
Monal S: Later. Everyone, check the announcement of motion if you joined recently. If you join now, you guys can check it.
Monal S: Rajesh, if you have holiday on Monday, the class will be as usual on another day. Alright?
Monal S: What is 21st?
Monal S: Shahid, we'll check with Krisha, okay?
Monal S: We'll check with Christian.
Monal S: See, when I'm… when I am going somewhere, then usually I give break, because you guys will still be, having that recording, right? But…
Monal S: We'll check it. If it is going to create an issue, we'll check it. Alright? Good morning, guys. Okay.
Monal S: Yes. Can we start the class, everyone? New day, new topic.
Monal S: Yes, let's not talk about anything else other than the class.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: Awesome, awesome.
Monal S: Hmm.
Monal S: Ballard School.
Monal S: So today is, guys, officially it is the third month of this year.
Monal S: And this year is very important for all of you. You're learning new things, you have to explore what you want to.
Monal S: what you want to be in this data field. Guys, even I am thinking about this data field now. I think the software engineer as a whole, as a whole industry.
Monal S: We have to update ourselves. I'm not sure whether AI is the main goal, software is the main goal. Right now, no individual knows the main goal.
Monal S: What they want to be, where they want to work.
Monal S: So I want all of you to keep an open mind, but having that understanding of technology will help you.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: I'm just… Putting my thought.
Monal S: Please elaborate.
Monal S: you… the statement itself is vague, the situation is also vague, so you will get vague statements. All of these things is in my mind.
Monal S: So yeah, everything is good.
Monal S: Everything is good.
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: So, if I talk about, agenda, let's talk about agenda.
Monal S: Guys, what is agenda of today's class? What is agenda of today's class?
Monal S: How many of you, were able to practice GitHub a little bit? GitHub.
Monal S: Push, pull…
Monal S: Great.
Monal S: It's just a tool, guys. It is not for development, it is… For… Things around development.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Rohit, if you are… you're doing something wrong, okay?
Monal S: Okay, alright guys, let's focus. Let's not talk about Git, else I will disable the check. Alright? So, let's talk about data visualization. Why do we even require data visualization? So, data visualization is the graphical representation, whatever we have learned till now, we have learned Python, right?
Monal S: Python is our programming language.
Monal S: NumPy is our core… our core library or framework which helps us do numerical computation, right? And then we have pandas.
Monal S: Panda helps us to manipulate the data, analyze the data, not directly analyze.
Monal S: Analyze is something that we have to do, but Pandas does not give you the analysis directly. You have to use Pandas to do that analysis, right? But Pandas will use NumPy. NumPy and Pandas will use NumPy. You will be able to load the data, perform whatever analysis you want to do on the data.
Monal S: Now, if I talk about certain kind of analysis, if I want to talk about analysis.
Monal S: Analysis of 2 years… of data.
Monal S: Okay? If I talk about analysis of 2 years of data, and in these 2 years, for each month, for each month, I will consider 10 days of data per month.
Monal S: Okay? 10 days of data, 10 days of data per month, per year. Alright? So, I will take this data similarly for 2 years.
Monal S: So, how many data points I will be having?
Monal S: How many data points I will be having. I have 12 months into 2 years, into 10.
Monal S: How many data points do you have?
Monal S: Tell me, guys, Another simple calculation?
Monal S: 240, okay? So here I have 240 data points. 240, whatever the numbers are. 240 is some kind of a number. And if I print, and if I print all these 240 data points.
Monal S: 240 rows of data. If I print all of this, will you be able to easily conclude what this data does?
Monal S: Will you be able to easily conclude what that data does?
Monal S: No. These are lots of data, 240 data points. I have to sort them out. Even after I sort them out, if I go to 100 through, if I go to 100 through, I will forget what happened in the 50. I will not be able to see it correctly, yes?
Monal S: I will not be able to remember it correctly.
Monal S: Yes, it would be very confusing. So, we as humans, we as humans, if I, if I ask you, if I ask you to remember
Monal S: to remember, 20… People, phone number.
Monal S: Will you be able to remember? Yes. Is it going to be hard? Very hard.
Monal S: I don't even remember a phone number of more than two people. I forget it easily. Yes, it will be a very hard task to remember 20 people's phone number, but if I ask you to remember
Monal S: 20 people faces.
Monal S: Which of the following scenario is simple?
Monal S: 1 or 2.
Monal S: Yes, second one, because we humans tend to, go in the direction, visual direction, okay? We are more of, visual beings.
Monal S: Then, remembering it. Numbers. Numbers are hard for us. Numbers is easy for computers, but it is hard for us. But visualization is something that is very easy for us.
Monal S: So, what we are going to do, instead of using these 240 data points and all the numbers, which is very hard for us to remember, why can't we use… why can't we use… let me write a different… write with a different color. Why can't we use plot?
Monal S: Plot is nothing but visualizations.
Monal S: Why can't we use plot, and plot all these 240 data points according to whatever the nature of the data is, we will use that plot. We can use bar plot, scatter plot, I will talk about all of that. But if we plot it, will we be easily able to remember if there is some kind of a trend here?
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Will we be easily able to remember it and do analysis when we have all of these graphs? Yes. We'll be able to see the pattern as a whole. We will be able to understand what happened in the previous one, what happened in the next month. That's why we use data visualization. Are we clear?
Monal S: Are we clear on the very base of why do we even require data analysis? Data visualization. Without data visualization, it is also fine, but visualization as human, helps us
Monal S: conclude a big picture in a single visualization, okay? So, it is the graphical representation of information and data.
Monal S: Data visualization is the graphical representation of information and data, and we use graphical representations, we use visual elements.
Monal S: we use… visual elements.
Monal S: Sure, no one.
Monal S: We use visual elements like charts, graphs.
Monal S: Map is also a visualization. If I ask you to remember the coordinate from X place to Y place, will you be able to remember it after 5 days? No.
Monal S: Map is also one of the visualization. Yes?
Monal S: And we use data visualization tools.
Monal S: To make it easier to see pattern, and we use these visual elements.
Monal S: We use these visual elements to see to see patterns.
Monal S: trends, and outliers.
Monal S: And large data set.
Monal S: Okay? Patterns, trends, and outliers. So, we as a data scientist, or as an AI engineer, alright, it is very important that we conclude something, that we conclude whatever our analysis is, whatever our data is, using the visual elements. Because
Monal S: Whatever we are working on, we are working on a task.
Monal S: Task, by default, is not technical. Task is some kind of a problem statement.
Monal S: A problem statement is not technical, but to understand that problem statement, to solve it, we have to use our technical knowledge. Yes.
Monal S: Yes, we have to use our technical knowledge to solve it. It can be coding, it can be apparent, it can be anything, but the conclusion of that technical knowledge should also be easily understandable. So this is the problem statement. Problem statement has been given us by business.
Monal S: Most of the problem statement that you will see in the industry is given by a business. So…
Monal S: Do you think that business people, people who are not from the technical coding background, is going to understand what you're going to say?
Monal S: If you say, sir, I've created 5 modules to solve this solution, does it even matter?
Monal S: Does this part matter?
Monal S: Does this part matter to the actual problem statement? No, they don't care. They will ask that we require a system like Chad GPT, where we can answer, where we can solve customer's query, whatever the domain is.
Monal S: That is a problem statement, where to solve it, we require a lot of technical, but at the end, at the end, we require some kind of a product, or some kind of an answer, which is directly related to the problem statement, not to the technical knowledge.
Monal S: So that's why the conclusion… the conclusion of any task should have some kind of a… Summary statistics… Visualization.
Monal S: Simple one, summary statistics visualization, so that you can tell business that this is what I have found, this is what you should do. Data scientists
Monal S: give, based on the data, they check what are the insights present in my data, and what are the next steps, what they are able to find, all the analysis. So, guys, you as a data scientist, as an AI engineer, it's not about visualization, I'm just telling that. You should be very good, you should be very good at
Monal S: concluding things. You should be very good at providing the summary to non-tech people. Are we clear? This is the skill that I also want you to have.
Monal S: Don't always talk. I see a lot of people, guys. I see a lot of people, they are technical people, and when they are asked for… they are asked to present some kind of a solution.
Monal S: They always talk in terms of the technical things that they have used, that the person they are presenting to, they don't even understand technology.
Monal S: So you should be very good at… just like I'm teaching you, if I have to teach you Git, if I have to teach you Git, I will create kind of a storytelling. Then you will understand all of it. So, that kind of things you should also have. Are we clear?
Monal S: Are you clear?
Monal S: Awesome.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: You should… data visualization, we will have coding, but we should use our logic, we should use our mind here, that whether this color is good, this… the way I'm presenting is good, there are a lot of things that you need to consider, okay? So let's talk about principles of…
Monal S: Good visualization.
Monal S: principles of… good visualization.
Monal S: What do you think should be present in a good visualization? Tell me. I'm just going to write down a few points here.
Monal S: What do you think should be present in a good visualization?
Monal S: Clarity.
Monal S: It should be clear on what that chart is telling. If I see a chart and I don't know what that chart is doing, I have the visualization, but is it good?
Monal S: No, it's not good. So, it should have a clarity, it means it should be easy to interpret.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Amor will talk about it, okay? Next, it should have proper scale.
Monal S: Okay? It should have proper skin. Suppose, on the x-axis, I'm talking about person. On the y-axis, I'm talking about height.
Monal S: If I don't write, if I again don't provide a clarity or something, do you think that if I choose a scale of height in kilometers.
Monal S: Okay? Or if I choose a height in meters.
Monal S: let's… let's think of my… US peoples will say, miles…
Monal S: And other will say kilometer, okay? So, if I choose height in kilometer, everyone's height will be in very small numbers. Yes or no?
Monal S: Various small numbers. Yes, I can plot it. That plot itself is not wrong, but the scale we are choosing is wrong.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Everyone?
Monal S: So, scale is also very important, what you want to show, okay?
Monal S: Again, it is for other people, it is not for us, so it should have a proper skill.
Monal S: Yes.
Monal S: Then, it should be very simple, okay? It should be very simple.
Monal S: It should follow minimalism.
Monal S: It should not have unnecessary things. The simple, the better. Lot of people, what they do, they will search in Python what are the best visualization libraries available. They will see the best one.
Monal S: They will plot it, the graph looks very fancy, but if it is very fancy, then again.
Monal S: it will have less clarity. People, someone needs to understand it, someone needs to learn it in order to even read it.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: So, it should be very simple, simple color, simple meaning, that's all. That's the main point of visualization.
Monal S: If someone has to learn visualization in order to read it, then it is not actually
Monal S: solving any problem. Okay? Next.
Monal S: We should label everything.
Monal S: Whenever we can.
Monal S: Okay? Whenever we can. So we will talk about it, we should label what is X-axis, what is Y-axis, what each of this value means. It means legend, we will talk about it later, and colors and everything, we should be… it should be present. So…
Monal S: Label everything you should do, okay? Next.
Monal S: use… color… wisely.
Monal S: It should not be like, this is your bar graph, this one is pink, this one is blue, this one is green, this one is black, this one is white. It is good, in some contexts, but a normal thing, if you want that, the better colors my graph is going to be, the better it is. No.
Monal S: It looks… it looks funny, okay? It should be very simple. You can use highlighted colors, but it should not be too distracting.
Monal S: Are you clear? It should not be too distracting. Simple. Visualization is supposed to be simple.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: Next, and the very important one.
Monal S: Yes, correct.
Monal S: Correct.
Monal S: Parikh, correct.
Monal S: Choose the… Correct chart.
Monal S: for your data. Very, very, very important.
Monal S: Alright? What are the different charts available? What are different things? We will talk about it, but choose the correct chart for your data. Are we clear?
Monal S: Guys, are we clear?
Monal S: I see. Okay.
Monal S: Little bit of theory is there, but these are the theory. It is not a part of data visualization, but I'm telling you beforehand so you can do better visualization.
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: Next, let's talk about… blocks.
Monal S: Okay, let's talk about plots.
Monal S: on.
Monal S: So now what I'm doing, I'm talking about scatter plot, okay? I'm talking about scatter plot.
Monal S: Hmm…
Monal S: Let me choose Line.
Monal S: I'm going to copy this, because I'm going to utilize it for other plots.
Monal S: And then let's start, okay? The first plot I am talking about is… Scatter block.
Monal S: Okay? Here, we have 2Xs.
Monal S: this, and this, alright? And here, let's suppose I have a lot of data of person, okay? This is person ID,
Monal S: This is person ID, and let's suppose I have a gym, and I want to keep track of people, people who are trying to lose weight. I want to check what is their width.
Monal S: and height. I does not change, but I'm just noting down height, okay? What is their width, and what is their height? And this will be person ID 1, and then I will have some kind of height. I'm just doing random dummy numbers, okay?
Monal S: 100… 300… 120… 350… 98…
Monal S: let's say 400 person ID 012, okay? I have these numbers. Now, let's suppose this is my width, this is my height.
Monal S: I'm starting from 50…
Monal S: 100, 150, 200, 250, 300. So starting from 50 all the way till 300, okay? This is my bit. If I talk about height, I'm starting from 100, 200, 300, 400, 500, okay? So this is height.
Monal S: 100 to 500. Now, if I want to plot all of these people, all of these people who are in membership with my gym, what I will do, I will plot each of them. Let's plot the person one.
Monal S: Okay? Let's plot person 1. Person 1 is 100 on the W, 100 on this axis, and 300 here.
Monal S: So, we will see somewhere points like this.
Monal S: Is this point clear, guys, how I plotted this?
Monal S: Is this point clear, how I plotted this? I plotted this using… This is Android.
Monal S: Okay, this is 100, this is 300.
Monal S: You will see the intersection here.
Monal S: Yes, everyone is clear?
Monal S: Next is 120, 350, so somewhere around here.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Somewhere around here is the next point.
Monal S: Next is 98, it means somewhere around here, then 400, it will be around here, okay? So what I'm doing, I'm just plotting this point. Don't worry about this yellow line, all you have to say is this orange one, okay? So think of it as, like, you have multiple people, you will have multiple points like this.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: So, a plot like this is called as scatter plot. Is everyone clear what is a scatter plot?
Monal S: Is everyone clear what is a scatter plot?
Monal S: Awesome.
Monal S: Okay, next.
Monal S: Let's talk about… guys, we will write the code. In that code, we are going to write the same thing, okay? We will pass a scatter plot, we will do all of that, but if you understand what each plot does, then it is very easy to do in the coding, alright? Next is line chart.
Monal S: Okay? Line chart. Line chart is used for, I will tell you… okay.
Monal S: We use line chart to see kind of a trend. Here, we are not seeing trend. This is more about groups of people. A scatter plot is about scattering all the data points, and if you're able to find some kind of a pattern here, then this is good. Line chart is used to see trend.
Monal S: Okay? It is used to see trend. Now, if I talk about what kind of data I will be using here, let me show you. Okay? So, let's suppose I have month here.
Monal S: Okay, I have month, and I have…
Monal S: I'm an insurance company, I want to check how much monthly revenue I am generating.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: how much monthly revenue I am checking. I am getting. So, month of January, let's suppose I got 12
Monal S: $120,000, okay? $120K. Then, on month of Feb, I got $140K, okay? The same thing, I'm writing with a different, K means $1,000, guys, okay? People who does not know. March.
Monal S: I got 180K in revenue, okay? Now, this is…
Monal S: my graph, and then what I'm going to do, I'm going to write, this is going to be by months.
Monal S: And this is going to be my revenue.
Monal S: Okay? This is month. Month 1, month 2, month 3, month 4, month 5.
Monal S: 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12. Okay? 1, all the way till 12. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. And then this is our revenue. Let's suppose all of this revenues is in… starting from 100K. 100K…
Monal S: 200K, 300K, 400K, 500K, or let's say 100… Android…
Monal S: 111, 112, 120, 130, 140, 150, 160, 170, okay? So this is… 100K.
Monal S: Yeah, whatever the number is, okay? Whatever the number is. Let's suppose this is…
Monal S: Alright? Just dummy numbers, guys. Suppose on a month of Jan, we got here. Let's not talk about the numbers, okay? On a month of Jan, I got somewhere around here. On month of Feb, I'm getting somewhere around here. On month of March, I'm getting somewhere around here, okay?
Monal S: Then, on month of…
Monal S: Next month, I'm getting here, but on 2 months, I got little less revenue as compared to the previous month, and then my trend is now leading up.
Monal S: Now, this is same like a scatter plot, but in sequence. But when we connect these dots, okay, but when we are going to connect these dots, then we are going to see the pattern.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Are we able to see the pattern?
Monal S: Yes, so it is used for trend. Whenever we want to… when someone says you… if you get a pro-off statement that I want to see.
Monal S: The, the trend over month, the accuracy over years, the change over years. It means they want to see the trend.
Monal S: So here, we are able to see some kind of a trend is present, and we'll be using line chart. See, if I use the scatter plot here for this data, it will also look fine, but scatter plot is used for something else, where we just need to plot some data.
Monal S: We can use scatterplot for this as well, it is totally fine, but we will not be able to see this line. This line is helpful here, yes? This line chart.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Sam, yes. Okay? Now let's talk about the next one.
Monal S: Let me copy this…
Monal S: I already had it, that's correct.
Monal S: Next, let's talk about… bar plots.
Monal S: Okay? It means it is going to have some bars.
Monal S: Alright? Here I have an X, here I will have a Y axis. Let's suppose I'm talking about,
Monal S: product. This is… Product, this is sales of product.
Monal S: This is sales of product. I want to see how much each product has been sold. What is the sales of each product, okay? So if I have product here, if I have product here, then I have sales.
Monal S: I will say this is my product A, this is a sales of product, A, sales of product B, sales of product B in dollars.
Monal S: Ganesh, am I not telling it?
Monal S: Guys, am I not telling it when we should use what graph?
Monal S: Literally, I'm giving you data set and plotting it.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Alright? You will understand, you will understand. Once you go to the data, you will see what data is good. Alright?
Monal S: So, I have product, and then I have sales. I want to… I want to see visually that which product is doing how much of sales. If I use line chart here, if I use line plot here, line… line chart here, I will see a dot.
Monal S: I will see a dot, and then another product, I will see dot. This one will tell me the trend. Am I looking for trend, or am I looking for separation, separation of products?
Monal S: I want to see products separated by their sales. I don't want them to be connected here. I want to see which product is doing good.
Monal S: So, line chart is not good, okay? I want to see comparison. Yes, I want to see comparison, but here I cannot see comparison. If I plot scatterplot, a scatterplot will give me data, but I… this is good.
Monal S: This is still good, but is there a better visualization? Yes. Bar plot is then better visualization. So, let me plot it.
Monal S: Only just how it looks like.
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: This color is better.
Monal S: So, product A… That's the age.
Monal S: This is product A, for example. All of this data are imaginary data, okay?
Monal S: Alright.
Monal S: Okay? And then we can write some of the names, just like I told you. Each data, if it has name, it is better. A, B, C, D, E, F,
Monal S: G, H. So, if I tell you, give me, I just want to see top 3 products. Tell me what are the top 3 products.
Monal S: What are the top 3 products?
Monal S: E is the first, then I can see A and C are second.
Monal S: Yes, EAC, AAC, whatever you want to call it. So, what I'm able to do easily, I'm able to compare them easily with a beautiful graph. Simple yet beautiful graph.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Awesome. Okay. Next.
Monal S: Do I have more space? Little bit of more space I have.
Monal S: Okay I have product ABC. This is product, let's suppose this is of category food.
Monal S: Now, I have another product, this is of category,
Monal S: Let's say… what do we have, another category?
Monal S: Let's say body care.
Monal S: BodyCare. Body care has its own product, ABC. BodyCare does its own sales.
Monal S: Dollar, dollar, dollar.
Monal S: So…
Monal S: Here, we are able to see that, let's suppose we have all the products, we have A to H in body care, we have A to H in food. Now, I have 2 products, 2 sales, I want to see both of them.
Monal S: I want to see both of them.
Monal S: Then what should I do?
Monal S: I can use two different plots, or I can merge two different plots. For food, I am using this blue. For food, I am using this blue, and…
Monal S: And for body care, I can use…
Monal S: Just a different color on top of the same graph.
Monal S: Guess?
Monal S: Are we able to see one of the disadvantages as well?
Monal S: What is one of the disadvantages? If it stacks on top of one, we… there is a possibility that we can… the other one can be hidden behind it. Yes, it is overlapping.
Monal S: Okay? It is overlapping. But if you do correct plotting here, if you write correct text that this is A, then you will see a text even though you're not able to see the actual plot. Are we clear?
Monal S: Are you clear?
Monal S: Okay? There are… guys, I'm just touching few plots here, but it's not about… it's not like I can teach you all of them in just doing the visualization in the notes, okay?
Monal S: I will only teach you a few, but in the code, we will see more. So this is called as stagg… let me write it clearly…
Monal S: stagged.
Monal S: bar block. Just a bar blot with stacked one.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: Done.
Monal S: Next. Are we clear on the use case, guys?
Monal S: Are we clear on the use case?
Monal S: Gonnage depends, scatter is usually the best, okay?
Monal S: Not distribution. Distribution is different.
Monal S: Yep.
Monal S: Alright, let's go to the next one.
Monal S: If I have some categories… see, everyone, I think everyone should know this, okay?
Monal S: Everyone should know this. If I say I have… Category. This is category.
Monal S: Different category, different category, and then I have their actual values out of the total, okay? I have percentages. Let's suppose I have 70, I have 10, I have 20 here, but all of them are adding up to some number. All of them are adding up to here, 100.
Monal S: Okay? All of them are adding up to 100, or just the total one, okay? If I have some kind of a category, okay, if I have some kind of a category, and I want to plot it, I want to see how… visually, that… what this number represents, which one is bigger, which one is smaller. What can we use here?
Monal S: Anyone, what can we use here?
Monal S: Simple pie chart.
Monal S: Okay? Pie chart.
Monal S: This will be my chart.
Monal S: And let's suppose that this is A category, B category, C category.
Monal S: And let me draw it.
Monal S: What is the best pillar here? I think… This will be good.
Monal S: All right?
Monal S: I'm just doing randomly guys.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: So, let's suppose this is category A, Category B, Category C. This is called as… pie chart.
Monal S: Bye, John.
Monal S: Okay? Bye jump.
Monal S: So, you will be able to see categories just like bar plot here, but bar plot is not used for percentages of each and every one. You… if you use bar plot components here, what will happen if two of the categories are same?
Monal S: Category A is 70, category B is 70. Yes, sales can have the same number, but what do we mean by 70 and 70?
Monal S: So, it is used for when we have a total of something. When we add something, we will get a number. Are we clear?
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: When we have a final total, usually it is used for percentages only, because percentages, the final count of any percentages is 100%. So, whatever category we are going to be, if we add all the percentages, it is going to be added to 100.
Monal S: Alright? Clear?
Monal S: Next, and the final one in this visualization part, then we will jump to the coding, alright? Then we will talk about data, coding, and others. Guys, there are a lot of other charts.
Monal S: I'm not going to use all of them here, okay? See, the point.
Monal S: What is one of the most important points here?
Monal S: clarity.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Ana Maria, are we clear?
Monal S: Sorry, Anne Maria.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Always use graphs and plots as easy as you can. Guys, trust me, I do presentation for bigger clients, and I've never seen them use fancy plots.
Monal S: If you use fancy, you're trying to make a presentation fancy, it's fine.
Monal S: You can do it.
Monal S: But no one has time to look at plots for more than 30 seconds or 1 minute.
Monal S: Okay, if you explain it, it is more than good.
Monal S: Okay? Presentation are not for 1 hour, it is only for 15 minutes, 20 minutes, then 10 minutes of discussion on top of that.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Alright, let's go to the next part.
Monal S: Next is box plot. This is also called as whisker plot.
Monal S: This is what we are going to use a lot as our data scientists. This tells us distribution and other points, okay? We'll talk about it.
Monal S: So, think of it as, like, we have a plot, and we use it to understand distribution of numerical columns.
Monal S: Are we clear? We use it to understand the data of numerical columns.
Monal S: So, this is my X, this is my Y. So, let's suppose I have different product. I have…
Monal S: product C1, I have product C2, then, this is a different column, two different columns, and I have products like this. Product 1, 2, whatever the number is. These are all numericals, okay? Then I have price.
Monal S: Price of C1, then I have price of C2, I have all of this information, alright? So I have 4 columns here, okay? This will be in terms of numbers. This will also be in terms of numbers, but can be floating. And here, what I'm trying to do… just wait… okay.
Monal S: Let's talk about the price of 4 different categories. Only price.
Monal S: Price of C3,
Monal S: Price of seafood. All of them are numbers, but now, because as I told you, guys, why did I choose price? Because one of the things that we learn is…
Monal S: proper scale. If I choose a category which the highest number is 100, and if I choose another category where the number is starting from 100K, do you think that scale is going to match in the same plot?
Monal S: No.
Monal S: Are you able to understand why we should not mix two things if they don't belong to the same category?
Monal S: So, that's why these principles are very important. I want you to remember all of this, okay?
Monal S: Okay? So, I have… I have 4 different categories.
Monal S: I don't worry about what is their tag or something. I just care about what is the price of each of these categories, okay? So, think of the data frame. Think of Apanda's data frame, where I have product A, product category is C1, category C1, but the product name can be different. If I talk about C1 as food.
Monal S: Let's suppose this is talking about
Monal S: frozen dumplings. Then I have the price. Then I have C2. Here, we are talking about
Monal S: Let's suppose another frozen category of
Monal S: Frozen, anything frozen? What is?
Monal S: Okay. Frozen, dry fruits, frozen vegetables, yes, frozen veggies, kebab, anything, right? I have its price. But what we are focusing on? Price of the category. Are we able to understand?
Monal S: price of the category. Is everyone clear?
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: We are not talking about individual items, we are more focusing on the category and their price range. So, what I want to understand from this graph… first, let's understand the problem statement. I want to understand, for each of these categories, what is the maximum? For each of these categories, what is the minimum? For each of these categories, what is the median? Median we will learn later, okay? I will talk about it more.
Monal S: what do… do we have any outliers? It means, do we have any products where the price is larger than as compared to others? If I talk about
Monal S: If I talk about, let's suppose, some food.
Monal S: Okay? This is… here we are talking about ice cream.
Monal S: Here, we're talking about frozen desert.
Monal S: And here, we will talk about, let's say, yes, frozen veggies.
Monal S: But now, there is one food item which is very fancy. It is… cold leaf ice cream.
Monal S: Yes, ice cream that has gold leaf on top of it. So the price of this is going to be very highest compared to other counterparts, yes or no?
Monal S: Yes or no?
Monal S: And if I plot it, let's suppose the ice cream is…
Monal S: $4, frozen dessert is $3, frozen veggies is $8, and this one is $20. As compared to other items, this one looks far, yes or no.
Monal S: This is a little far, yes or no?
Monal S: So, if I want to see some kind of things which is far from the other groups, we call that as outliers. Are we clear, guys? What is an outlier? Are we clear?
Monal S: Any data that is far from the generic group, that is called as outlier.
Monal S: So, if I want to understand all of this 4-5 information, okay, I want to understand all of this 4-5 information of a particular category.
Monal S: But I have multiples of them. I can use a single plot, that is box plot. It will tell us all this information in a single plot.
Monal S: Are you clear? I will tell you how it does it, okay?
Monal S: Alright. Okay? So, it tells you distribution also.
Monal S: More in depth, I will talk about it later, but let me plot some bar.
Monal S: Let's use a different color this time.
Monal S: Dull color.
Monal S: Okay? Maybe use this one.
Monal S: Okay? So it has few data points.
Monal S: Let me… I think I am leaving a few things.
Monal S: And then let me also show you.
Monal S: It is it.
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: Say this.
Monal S: The bottom part of this plot, let's only talk about this, okay? The bottom part is the minimum value.
Monal S: The bottom part is the minimum value.
Monal S: The bottom part is minimum. This part is the maximum range. Minimum range, maximum range. Okay? This one is called as Q1.
Monal S: Okay? This one is called as Q3, and the center one is called as median.
Monal S: Okay? This is the median of the full data. If I have a row, if I have a column, numerical column, if I do median of all the data, I will get median. So this center line represents median.
Monal S: This one represents Q3, this one represents Q1. Q1 and Q3, I will talk about it, okay? These are 25 and 75 percentile of the data.
Monal S: Okay? These are 25, and… So, let me write… Where is it? Yep.
Monal S: median, or 50 percentile, 50 percentile, this one is 21st percentile, this one is 75 percentile. And this box, you are able to see.
Monal S: This range you are able to see is called as IQR. These are all the statistics things. But are you able to see that it provides a lot of information in a very small area?
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: And this will be price.
Monal S: X axis is products.
Monal S: categories.
Monal S: Categories, and this is price.
Monal S: Okay? IQR is called as intercotile range, don't worry about it, I will teach you all of that in depth. But, using the single plants, this is for Category 1. Similarly, if we have Category 2, Category 3, and Category 4, it tells us each and everything.
Monal S: Alright, how to radiate, what are different values, we'll talk about that later. Alright, are we clear? What is a box plot, guys?
Monal S: Aren't we clear what is a box plot?
Monal S: So, box plot tells us, as I told you, box plot is more for us, more for technical people than for business people. It tells us all of this information of the data set.
Monal S: And we will be able to know what is the distribution of the data set, how my dataset is, lined up, whether it has outliers or not. So when we know what is the median outliers, then we will do our data analysis feature engineering to fix the data, to remove some of the data, we will do all of that.
Monal S: Are we clear? So this is… it gives us these data points that we, as technical people, will use it to further improve our data later on.
Monal S: Are we clear? It is for technical people.
Monal S: Yeah, candlestick… Candlestick chart, I think it is a box plot only.
Monal S: They appear very similar, but they are not, okay?
Monal S: Candlestick is more for financial data, it is for use for low case and others, while box plot is for different, okay? Candlestick does not have all of these properties, it is specifically made for financial data.
Monal S: Alright? For open, high, low, close.
Monal S: Santosh will talk about that later. Guys, there are a lot of things.
Monal S: Guys, still there are a lot of plots that are left, but this gives us overview of… see, we have seen overview of 6 different plots.
Monal S: Okay? Later we will see how to use it, how to write a code of it, but are we able to get a clarity of what data visualization is? Our main agenda is not to plot and learn everything in a single go.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Let's not talk about outlier or something, I will teach you that part. If I'm not teaching you something right now, I will teach you later. Okay? Trust me.
Monal S: I'll link.
Monal S: Are you guys enjoying the class?
Monal S: Different class than before?
Monal S: Every module is different, guys. Every module requires a different kind of teaching method, okay? Not everything is same.
Monal S: Right? Let's go to the next prompt.
Monal S: Yes. Okay.
Monal S: So now what I'm going to do, I will talk about some dataset which we are going to use, and I already have the dataset here, okay?
Monal S: online retail data set. Is the dataset CSV, or something else? This is an Excel file.
Monal S: Guys, this is an Excel file. Am I able to see Excel file here?
Monal S: Currently, I'm not able to see. Let's… let me check.
Monal S: If it works or not.
Monal S: This one is not working. So let's look for extension where I can get Excel Viewer or something.
Monal S: Or I need to install and update it again.
Monal S: This is Excel Viewer, I already have it, but for some reason it is not working. So let me restart it, enable it, and let's see if it works or not.
Monal S: If not, I can download a different extension.
Monal S: See, this one, I don't think so that this is working here. So let's look for a different extension. This is Excel Viewer. Let me disable it.
Monal S: Unstall it, okay?
Monal S: Do I have anything else? With the highest number of…
Monal S: Ratings. This one is having…
Monal S: See this, this one is HTML, only one star, this one is 232, this one is XL99K.
Monal S: I think this would look pretty good.
Monal S: Because this is Excel to Markdown, this is a little different.
Monal S: Yeah, we escort sometimes a lot differently.
Monal S: Chinese one?
Monal S: No, it has a language one as well. Alright,
Monal S: Okay, I think it changed some of the forms as well.
Monal S: It installed some font things, now things look different in my system, but let's click on it.
Monal S: Let's see if it is working or not.
Monal S: It is taking a lot of time, I'm not sure how big this data is.
Monal S: Alright, in the meantime, what we can do, we can check this… about this data online. We will still be able to read it using Pandas. Pandas will be… yes, see this?
Monal S: Are you able to see the data?
Monal S: I think this is good, okay? This is good.
Monal S: And we are able to see that it has two sheets, year 2009-2010, and then year 2010-2011. We have two different sheets here. But to more… to know more about this dataset, I will show you where did I got this dataset, okay?
Monal S: Don't worry, I will share the link with all of you. So, this is the dataset. This is in Archive ICS. If you want to learn more about dataset, or want to explore multiple datasets, this is the website which you can check.
Monal S: ics.ucci.edu. You can see it is a machine learning repository. If you go there, you will see all this popular data set. You might find Titanic here as well. Let's see if we have Titanic, let me search.
Monal S: Do we have Titanic here?
Monal S: Maybe not.
Monal S: Do we have Titanic?
Monal S: This one does not have titanium.
Monal S: Okay? But this one has other modes. So if you can click on dataset, you will be able to see how many dataset it has.
Monal S: You can choose any one of them and can do your own analysis, but we'll talk about that later. But what dataset I'm using is online retail, okay? This data set is online retail.
Monal S: I've sent in the chat, okay? So this is… everyone focus. Let me disable the chat.
Monal S: You guys, don't focus, and then we'll ask at the end, sir, what is the data set, okay? Everyone?
Monal S: This is a transactional data, which… data set which comes with all the transactions occurring between this date till this date for a UK-based and registered non-store online retail, okay? It means some kind of an online shop, non-store, okay?
Monal S: online retain.
Monal S: So here, this dataset has multiple, you can say, personalities. One is multivariate, sequential, time series, we will talk about that again later, but it has integer as well as real data, it is business category, it has around
Monal S: 540… 1000 data, 540K data.
Monal S: And then, it is used for classification and clustering. It has 6 number of columns. Features means 6th number of columns.
Monal S: Data center information, the same thing is present here, but with more information. Many customers of the company are wholesalers, okay? Whatever the data is, this company mainly sells unique all-location gifts. Many customer of companies are wholesalers itself, so you will see the data.
Monal S: So here you will see invoice number. Invoice number is categorical, here we are able to see it is a categorical type. A 6-digit integer… integral number uniquely assigned to each. You can read about all of this, okay? But you can see, this starts with letter C. That's why it is categorical. It is starting with a letter C,
Monal S: That's why it is not directly an integer. If you remove C… yes, okay.
Monal S: Not C. If the code starts with letter C, it indicates cancellation. I'll be clear. In an invoice, if it is a number, then it is an invoice.
Monal S: If it starts with C, it means that invoice was, was canceled, okay? That is invoice number. Stock code, we have 5-digit, again, integral number.
Monal S: for the ID… this is, again, an ID type, this description is a feature, product name, okay? What is the description of it? Quantity, quantity of each item per transaction. In each transaction, what was the quantity? What is the invoice date?
Monal S: Product per price unit is the unit price here. Customer ID, we already have it. This is the customer ID, and this is the country.
Monal S: Are we clear, everyone, what this dataset is?
Monal S: You can download this dataset, this is online retail, but I will also attach in the resource. You can see, download button is also there. Super clear, everyone's clear.
Monal S: Don't say, tell me, sir, working with real industry data set.
Monal S: I'm literally annoyed with that, but people who say, what is industry project? I don't understand what is industry project. Even after working with industry so long, I feel like…
Monal S: every project is industry project. If you make it with a good standard.
Monal S: Guys, it does not have a URL. If you click on import, you have to install this,
Monal S: frame this library, and then you will be able to use this ID which they are giving the code. You'll be able to load it. But I will suggest to download, and then use the Excel to load into the bundles. Clear?
Monal S: Are we here?
Monal S: Yes, if you talk about the URL, if I show you this data set, let me see.
Monal S: Okay, let me see if there is any way to directly access it. If I click on download, what will happen?
Monal S: Oh, it started downloading.
Monal S: See this?
Monal S: It's in zip.
Monal S: Okay, it is downloading.
Monal S: But I think I found this dataset somewhere else.
Monal S: I found the URL, see this, it is 352, and I have one URL that I found from internet, and if you search this URL,
Monal S: You can see download is starting. Yes?
Monal S: the same data set download is starting. So, I have this URL, which I will be using it to load it, okay? I will share that later, but I will not suggest anyone to do coding side by side.
Monal S: Can I move forward, guys?
Monal S: If all the routes are cleared, Next. Okay?
Monal S: Now you can see, that is the file link that I downloaded. I will provide the same link here, dataset link.
Monal S: dataset link.
Monal S: Here, this is the dataset link. You guys can download it later.
Monal S: And, or you can directly, load it from this URL itself, dataset link.
Monal S: No.
Monal S: I have downloaded this dataset and kept inside folder. You can see 0103, there is a dataset already here, the same dataset, XLXX. Now, if I try to load this dataset.
Monal S: if I say pd.readxl, you can see we have read CSV, read clipboard, read Excel, read Feather, read HTML, read JSON, read Market, parkit is another file. We have a lot of files here.
Monal S: Okay? Guys, it will take time, because it is having 5 60,000 rows of data, it will take time.
Monal S: Alright, it will take time. So this is what I want to do, guys, which function I should select. Read Excel, because it is an Excel file. And if I provide Excel file, we should see one kind of error. Let's see whether we are getting error or not.
Monal S: I'm providing this URL, or better, this URL is already present in my system. I will copy the relative path, paste it here.
Monal S: Let me set this to the standard, that is, forward slash, and done.
Monal S: Okay? And in this sheet, what sheet, guys, when you load something with Python, you need to write what sheet you want to read. What sheet we want to read? Let's read only one sheet at a time. Okay? Year 2009-2010. So we need to pass sheet name.
Monal S: Sheet name is equals to… Year 2009, same exact name you should pass.
Monal S: Otherwise, it will not load. And then I will say this is my data frame one, because I have multiple data frame.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Also, because we are already present… our file is already present inside this, we should not write it. Yes, correct amount. Let's do it.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: Or dot slash, from the relative path, do this.
Monal S: What is the error? Okay, first we need to load the pandas.
Monal S: And then, let's see… What are we getting?
Monal S: We are getting one error. It is saying, import open PIXL failed. It means
Monal S: This particular method which I'm using, it uses some of the library which we don't have. It is not able to import it. So it means we need to… it means we need to install it. Are we clear?
Monal S: It means we need to install it, so let me open CMD.
Monal S: Activate the UV, Okay, activate the UV.
Monal S: Where is my UV?
Monal S: This font that it gives me, it looks good.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Okay, level 2, we're already in level 2. Then what we need to do? UV add, and then whatever the error for the library we have. It is getting import, if it is trying to import, means this is the library, yes?
Monal S: So if I copy it, paste it, UV add, open pi Excel.
Monal S: Let's see.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: The same will be reflected in… White or Siamen.
Monal S: Pye Project YAML.
Monal S: Alright, here. Now let's try to load it.
Monal S: We are going to import pandas, dataset is a command, and read it.
Monal S: Are you able to read it?
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: So, mate, we'll talk about it. It's a jellyfish, but now that I installed that, thing, it installed some kind of icon bag as well.
Monal S: done. This part is done. I'm able to load the data frame. Let's see…
Monal S: Let's see the info. Info will give us what are the different info. You can see it is around 32.1 plus MB it is using. Is it a lot?
Monal S: Is this allowed?
Monal S: Is this a lot of MV? Guys.
Monal S: As compared to our system, it's not a lot. Can we say that this is a huge dataset? Let's not look at entries. Can we say this is a huge dataset?
Monal S: Nope.
Monal S: I have seen data set which is consuming 1.4 GB700MB of our RAM, of our memory. As compared to that, this is nothing.
Monal S: 102MB, very, very small data. That's why we don't have to do any kind of optimization, okay? Now, what I will do, I will create a new one.
Monal S: First, Let me delete it.
Monal S: I will tell you why I'm deleting, because this is using RAM, right? So we can remove some of the RAM. Delete DF1, delete it. Remove from the RAM. Now, what I want to do, I want to run this again, but this time we have another sheet. Yes or no?
Monal S: We have another sheet. Another sheet name is 2010 to 2011.
Monal S: Now I want to load both of them.
Monal S: So, DF1, DF2, I have 2 data frame. Loading both of them, let's see how much time it takes.
Monal S: As I told you, we'll be learning Pandas. We'll be using Pandas, but learning more things of it when to use one.
Monal S: It's going to take time.
Monal S: If we have data source in share path, can we use it? You can use it.
Monal S: You can use this directly.
Monal S: Your system will be… okay, how many of you have completed the assignment of…
Monal S: downloading that data, which I told you.
Monal S: How many of you have done it, that assignment? How many of you have not done it?
Monal S: downloading something from the Python.
Monal S: How many of you have not done it, and tell me why.
Monal S: Tell me why you have not done it, guys.
Monal S: People are sharing, literally, the code.
Monal S: Completed on the same day, that's a great review. Others… Today's class pace is good.
Monal S: Guys, today's class space is good.
Monal S: You didn't get time to work on it, guys? When will you get time?
Monal S: You will never get time. I'm not saying this to you. Even I, I want to do a lot of things. I will never get time. I have to…
Monal S: Just use ChatGPT and understand it.
Monal S: Yes, so guys, please…
Monal S: Okay, sir, I joined. It's fine, people who joined recently, you don't have to worry about assignments. I'm asking for others, okay?
Monal S: Okay, please complete it, it will give you a better understanding of
Monal S: how data comes. I want you to understand the whole thing about downloading something, okay? Then you will understand that people who have done it, if I try to read from this one, do we know the intermediate process of what Python will be doing it?
Monal S: people who have done the assignment and understood the assignment, now do you know that when I provide this link, Python has to read it byte by byte.
Monal S: And until it is stored in our RAM,
Monal S: We cannot read it. Yes, Others…
Monal S: Guys, why are you so quiet?
Monal S: Everyone is so cold.
Monal S: Yes.
Monal S: Debajyotri, you will find in the resource section, all the notebooks, okay?
Monal S: Great.
Monal S: Alright? So, that thing, if you want to understand it more deeper, that what happens when you provide link, once you complete that assignment, it will give you better clarity.
Monal S: Deva, I will provide you this link, okay? Deva?
Monal S: Let's focus here. So now that I have two different data frames, this is df.info, and I have another data frame. This is DF2 of info. Both of them belongs to a different, year itself. You can see, it has
Monal S: 541,000 rows. This one is 525,000 rows.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Now, what we are going to do, because these are two… let's first check, do they have same number of columns?
Monal S: Here we have 0 to 7, here we have 0 to 7. Let's check the column.
Monal S: Do we have same number of columns? DF.columns?
Monal S: This is df.columns.
Monal S: And then… BF2.columns.
Monal S: Let's enclose them in list.
Monal S: Think about that.
Monal S: List, this one is list.
Monal S: Are they both same?
Monal S: Same exact column name, I feel like they are safe.
Monal S: Yes, I feel like they are same.
Monal S: And, other things are also the same. Total number of 8 columns. So, what we can do, we have two data frames instead of working with two. Yes, to extract it, we require to extract in two different data frames. Now, what I will do, I will merge data frame. So, I will put DF1
Monal S: on top of DFD.
Monal S: So, DF2 will be at the bottom, okay? Then DF1, so that it can follow the same time sequence. So, what I will do, I will use pd.concat.
Monal S: I told you we'll be learning pandas as we go, okay? concat, the first data frame, and then I want to merge the second data frame, I want to CONCAT.
Monal S: Concord is the right term here, yes.
Monal S: And what we want, we want to ignore the index.
Monal S: Tell me, why do we want to ignore the index?
Monal S: Harsh, is it the same data?
Monal S: Guys, is DF1 and DF2 the same data?
Monal S: Why are you saying, why are you merging the same data?
Monal S: This is a different year, this is a different year.
Monal S: Please don't do coding side by side.
Monal S: So what are we doing? We are concatenating one data frame on top of another. We are ignoring index, a lot of you have answered correctly, we are ignoring index because this data frame will again be starting from 0 or 1. This is already starting from 0 and 1, so we will see multiple duplicates index, that is not something which we want.
Monal S: So, we want pandas to ignore the index when you're doing the concatenation, and then I will create a final data frame of DF.
Monal S: Alright, this is final data frame of DF. So now we can see, print, DF.shape.
Monal S: In short, it can give me how many rows of data that we have. Is this huge now? In terms of total number of rows, it is huge. In terms of memory, it is not that, okay? Because it is only 8 columns. This is a huge data.
Monal S: It is around 10 million data, yes?
Monal S: 1 million rows of data, yes. It is around 1 million rows of data.
Monal S: Okay? Now, if you want to check what are the different columns available, do df.columns. These are the columns. Because all of the columns are good, that's why we are able to CONCAT it. Otherwise, it would have given us error that you are trying to merge two different data frames. You cannot do CONCAT.
Monal S: Alright, you cannot do CONCAT on that. Just wait, guys.
Monal S: Tangman, we'll kind of get an error, or our index will not be correct.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Let's move forward to the next spot, okay?
Monal S: So this is our DF, and if you want to see the head, df.head.
Monal S: We told it to ignore the original index, but Pandas will provide its own index. Okay? So here we can see the same invoice. Guys, invoice ID is same, but description is different. It means it is a different, different product that belongs to the same invoice.
Monal S: Yes or no? We have a single invoice, we have different products, each of these products have different quantity, and we have country, the country customer ID is there, we have the price of each of this product code. Stock code is product code.
Monal S: This one is having a different price, this one is having a different price, this one is having a different price. Are we clear? See this description? 20 lights, pink cherry lights, white cherry lights, record frame, single size, all of this. So if I do df.head of 10,
Monal S: This person has… this is a single invoice, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8. For this particular invoice, it has around 8 items.
Monal S: Are we able to understand, guys, how this dataset is?
Monal S: Everyone?
Monal S: This whole thing belongs to a single invoice, but each transaction in the invoice is a separate entry in this data frame.
Monal S: Yes, submit.
Monal S: Because it internally uses it, so it is competitive. Okay? Next.
Monal S: What I want to do, let's talk about
Monal S: it will give you a hint on what we do in the actual feature engineering. So the next is cleaning and feature engineering, just on a high level, okay? So what I will check here, I will check df.info. Timir, because they provided it, guys.
Monal S: Do we have any control of what we are downloading?
Monal S: If they have written it as .0, it means it is a float. If you convert to num integer, it will not have 0.
Monal S: Rajiv?
Monal S: If I'm writing it, you can check it.
Monal S: Okay, guys, don't… I… Rajiv, I know you're doing coding.
Monal S: People who are doing coding alongside the class, the guys, that is not good.
Monal S: It breaks the flow of the class.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Please don't do coding.
Monal S: I've sent it, this is the sheet name.
Monal S: Okay, now let's do a little bit of data cleaning and feature engineering. You can see, let's check how many columns have few null values. This non-null means it has these many non-null values.
Monal S: If it is matching with total number of entries, it means it has no null values. This is good.
Monal S: Does it have null values? No.
Monal S: Does it have null values? No. Does it have null values? Yes, a bit.
Monal S: Does it have null values? No. Does it have null values? No. No.
Monal S: Does this have null values?
Monal S: Yes, we are missing lot of customer IDs.
Monal S: We are not missing any control. So guys, this is how we read data. We are technical people. We will read data like this.
Monal S: How fast it is in pandas.
Monal S: To do the same… guys, I'm not an Excel expert, but tell me how fast you can do all of this information in Excel.
Monal S: People who know Excel tell me how fast you can do all of this in Excel.
Monal S: Harish is saying it's quite difficult in Excel.
Monal S: It will take a lot of time. But in Pandas, DF.info.
Monal S: In Pandas, it is df.info, but in Excel, to get this information, it will take a lot of time.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Alright, so now let's see which of the following columns is unnecessary for us.
Monal S: Which of the following columns feel unnecessary for now?
Monal S: For now, I feel like if I want to plot some kind of something with… if I want to plot price.
Monal S: with invoice, invoice is important, because I know that if I want to get some analysis on… guys, I'm just talking about, there is no problem statement. Sometimes you will get data, then you will think that, what can we do with this data?
Monal S: So, for now, I'm thinking…
Monal S: This invoice ID is very important because it tells me how many products have been bought by a customer. Yes.
Monal S: Yes? Can I get this analysis?
Monal S: how many products I can get.
Monal S: Based on the customer, or based on the invoice.
Monal S: This is one of the analysis. Second is, this is invoice date. Invoice date, I can use, I can check that how many of the invoice I create in a particular day.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: how many invoices I create in a particular day as a manufacturer or as a seller.
Monal S: Yes? Tell me yes or no.
Monal S: Okay? Then I have customer ID. This customer ID is 13085. For me, I think that customer ID is something that, when that customer is going to buy it again, they are going to have a new ID.
Monal S: I feel like it is going to be like that.
Monal S: So, they are going to create a new ID. So, think of it as… for now. For now, let's understand that this customer ID, whenever someone joins, it will create again a new ID. Okay? This is just a scenario.
Monal S: I'm not saying this is the truth here, but this is just a scenario. So, if I don't want this feature, guys, if I don't want this feature, what I can do?
Monal S: I can remove it.
Monal S: I can remove it, okay.
Monal S: I can remove, but for now, let's not remove. For now, let's check… let's solve one issue at a time, okay? Let's solve one issue at a time.
Monal S: For now, tell me which of the following columns have null in them.
Monal S: Which of the following columns have null in them?
Monal S: Customer ID?
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Now, I will tell you a scenario.
Monal S: For any invoice.
Monal S: for any invoice, if it does not have a customer ID, it means that it is not noted in the system that can be… that can have some kind of error as well. Yes or no? Any invoice that does not have customer ID, it can be wrong as well.
Monal S: This is about judgment for now. It can be wrong as well. So, it is better to remove any row that has customer ID as null. Are you able to understand what I'm saying? Let's remove any rows that has customer ID as null. We will remove that whole row itself.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Okay, so what I will do…
Monal S: Let's go to the code, and here I will write dataframe.
Monal S: Drop any.
Monal S: which column I want to drop? I want to drop the subset of Subset of data, where
Monal S: the column customer ID, if any of them is NA, I will drop it. DF equals to DF.drop NA.
Monal S: Now, let's see, df.info.
Monal S: Do we have… now, you can see all the rows are now equal to the same number of non-null rows of customer ID, yes or no?
Monal S: Yes, customer ID previously was 824364, number of non-null rows. Now we have standardized all of them, we have truncated all the data, now all the data has customer ID.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: All the data has customer ID now.
Monal S: Is everyone clear?
Monal S: Now, let's check this index.
Monal S: Is all the row… all the columns having same number of rows as total number of rows in the data frame?
Monal S: Or do we have… still have null values? Do we still have null values in this new data frame?
Monal S: No.
Monal S: No null values.
Monal S: Okay? Now let's see a few things.
Monal S: Let me check… this is my data frame.
Monal S: DF.log, let me zoom in, and let me… df.log.
Monal S: what I want to do this time, I want to check 100 to 200.
Monal S: Are we able to see any invoice starting from C?
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: So, if I have to do analysis on what is my total price, whatever my quantity is, whatever it is, do you think that the invoice that got canceled is a good thing to have in the dataset?
Monal S: No.
Monal S: If it is canceled, it means my… I have not increased my sales, my product quantity still removes the same, so it's better to remove
Monal S: Next problem statement is, let's remove the cancellation invoices.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: So what I want, I want a data frame, and I will do some operation on the data frame.
Monal S: Now, what I want to do, I want to work with what column?
Monal S: I want to work with invoice column. So, I will say, in this one, I want to work with
Monal S: invoice column. First invoice column, I will convert to S type, because
Monal S: What is the type of invoice? It is already your object. Let's convert to STR first.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Just to be safe, convert to STR, because we are going to perform STR. And what do we want?
Monal S: SDR dot starts with C.
Monal S: Do we know this?
Monal S: Even though we have not learned a very specific method, but do we know what it does? So what this is doing, this one is saying, give me a data frame. What is the condition? This is saying, give me all the invoice rows where the rows start with C.
Monal S: Now tell me, do we want to remove C, or we want all the rows start with C?
Monal S: This one is giving all the rows start with C. Is this correct?
Monal S: Is this correct?
Monal S: This is not correct. This will give me all the rows that start with C, but we want to remove all the rows that start with C. So what we will do, we need to do something. It means we need to do the opposite. If I do the opposite of this, will that give me all the rows, all the data without C?
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Yes, so there is this particular symbol that you will find on top of tear. This is called a tilde, T-I-L-T-E. This will do the opposite of it.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: See this? What this function is?
Monal S: It does the invert.
Monal S: Arabic layer, it does the invert, opposite of it.
Monal S: Okay, please explain one more time, because you have to improve your logic.
Monal S: In my data frame, I have 123456, C123456, C489. I have my invoice.
Monal S: My target is… Get all the rows… without C.
Monal S: get all the rows without C. What I will do.
Monal S: I want anything except these two, yes?
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: But, currently, what I'm saying, currently what I'm saying, I'm saying
Monal S: Give me all the rows, if I… whatever I selected, see this highlighted one?
Monal S: whatever I have selected, here I am saying, give me all the rows which is starting from C.
Monal S: Is this the logic we require?
Monal S: No.
Monal S: What we require is, we require the opposite of what we are doing here.
Monal S: Opposite of selecting C is… oppose it of… selecting… Invoice… Start with C is.
Monal S: Start with C is.
Monal S: Rose… or invoice… that… does not start with C, Are we clear?
Monal S: Guys, are we clear? So that's why, if this is giving me all the rows starting with C, then I want the opposite of it, this is inward.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: This is invert of that, and if I do it, Let's see the shape now.
Monal S: Let's see the shape, df.shape.
Monal S: Previously, it was… Previously, it was 824364.
Monal S: If I do 824364, that was original, minus 805620,
Monal S: How many rows we have removed? 18,744 rows we have removed.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Good. Are you able to understand the use case of Python now? Pandas?
Monal S: Pandas is good.
Monal S: Guys, Parandas is amazing, okay? Me, personally, I think that Parandas is amazing.
Monal S: How are you selecting STR starting with C, Satish?
Monal S: Anyone?
Monal S: Can we use trim to remove C? Guys, if we use trim to remove C,
Monal S: Will it solve the actual issue that the invoice got canceled?
Monal S: Guys, what are we talking about?
Monal S: It will only remove C. We have… we are talking about data here.
Monal S: Are we clear? So, removing C will not clear the issue.
Monal S: None.
Monal S: Next.
Monal S: SIM itself means that the invoice is canceled by the customer, so it means that invoice is no use for us.
Monal S: So, if you want to see how many invoices got canceled, it is 18,744.
Monal S: Yes, alright? So what time it is? 1029, just let me give you the final thing, then we will jump, because after this analysis, I will start with the matplotlib, okay? One thing. Now I want to remove… let's remove anything that has zero or negative quantities, because we have seen that we have negative as well.
Monal S: If quantity is negative, what does it even mean?
Monal S: It can mean something to the manufacturer, but for us, because we don't have the clarity, it's better to remove it for now.
Monal S: Until we have 100% clarity, let's remove it, okay? So, it will probably, most of the time, it will be something that got canceled. Yes.
Monal S: Whenever we… something… the invoice got canceled, this is kind of a return. But for now, we will check if there is any other case.
Monal S: Can you say 100% that negative will not be present when they… when the invoice is not seen?
Monal S: Can we say 100% for now?
Monal S: No. So, to make sure… we will use pandas. We are developers, we have to make sure, yes? So, I will do…
Monal S: the column called as quantity. This is quantity. And let's also fix the price, where the price is negative. Yes, price can also be negative in some of the cases. We will see that.
Monal S: So first, I will do…
Monal S: Any quantity that is greater than zero, I want to keep it. Is this fine? I want to keep all the rows where the price is greater than zero. And after that, I will do DF.shape.
Monal S: The previous was 805620, let's see.
Monal S: Is it same?
Monal S: Is it same? It means our conclusion of we will only see negative in the quantity when, when the invoice is having… when the invoice is having C at the start.
Monal S: Second, What I want? Price.
Monal S: When the price is negative, we don't want that rose.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: So… See this case?
Monal S: When we already removed all the cases where the quantity is negative, why do we have a price negative as well?
Monal S: If we would have taken the fact that price will be negative when the C is negative… when we have C, it was wrong.
Monal S: So, in data, when we talk about data, don't directly conclude anything until your data says it.
Monal S: Yes, we were wrong.
Monal S: We were wrong about price.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: So, guys, always make sure your data scientist.
Monal S: You're not analysis scientists, okay?
Monal S: So, the few price, which was negative, got removed, okay?
Monal S: Done. Now, what we will do, finally.
Monal S: Guys, if I want revenue, if I want revenue, how can I choose revenue?
Monal S: If I want, is there any column called as revenue here?
Monal S: No.
Monal S: I don't have any revenue. If I talk about invoice, I have quantity, I have price, I don't have revenue.
Monal S: if I want, what is the total price of this… what is the total sum of this invoice?
Monal S: If I want to check what is the total value of this invoice, this particular invoice.
Monal S: I will use quantity multiplied by price, yes?
Monal S: So let's create new.
Monal S: If I do this… DF quantity multiplied by DF price, I will get revenue. Yes?
Monal S: Next…
Monal S: Final two lines of code before the break, db.info. Now, let's talk with invoice date. Invoice date currently is date time, so this is already correct. If it was not date time, what we will be doing?
Monal S: If it is non-date time, what we will be doing?
Monal S: PD.2Drate time? Yes.
Monal S: Of this particular column, we will store back to invoice date.
Monal S: Now, if I want to extract… if I… now that I've done it, next thing I want is, I also want to get the column column… the month column of each invoice. I want to get what month we have sold them.
Monal S: What should I do?
Monal S: We have something called as DT.2 period, okay? Guys, there are a lot of things, but are you familiar with this thing?
Monal S: Are we familiar with this thing?
Monal S: Yes, we are familiar.
Monal S: Done. Let's see the final data frame.
Monal S: DF.Ed, Are we able to see month information?
Monal S: 2009-12, 2009, 12. Is it helpful? It will be helpful later, in one of the analysis.
Monal S: So, today's data visualization mark, right? Data visualization works with correct data. That's why we are doing all of this. Is this fun?
Monal S: Are you guys enjoying the class?
Monal S: Please repeat the data part once, guys.
Monal S: I want month from the invoice data. Invoice data is already date. I'm converting dt.to period of month, so it will give me 2 period is another one of it. What it does, it accepts
Monal S: This frequency… see this, this is two period.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: What it does? It returns this two-period run type, and then we need to check what it does.
Monal S: Okay, see this.
Monal S: Bound series, we need to check a lot of that. To period.
Monal S: Okay? But what it is done, it… when we pass month, it will return us what is the month.
Monal S: As well as the year it belongs to.
Monal S: Okay? As well as the year it belongs to.
Monal S: tt.month. You can see 12th month, 11th month, you will see.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: Can't understand and catch you up now, I have to practice bandhas. Guys.
Monal S: You don't have to remember each and everything. Are we able to understand why I'm doing each and every step?
Monal S: Are we able to understand why we are doing each and every step? That's all you need to know.
Monal S: Ask said GPT if I don't remember something, but is the code very hard to understand?
Monal S: Code is not hard. Code is not at all hard.
Monal S: Don't worry about syntax.
Monal S: Syntax is present in the Google. You are living in AI era.
Monal S: If you're talking about 10 years back, I would have told you to remember each and every syntax in the copy.
Monal S: Now you don't require it, okay? So, this completes our data. So, we are doing all of this, so when we have… once we have the clear data, then we can understand the underlying insights on that data.
Monal S: Alright? Underlying insights of the data. Then all it is possible.
Monal S: So, this part is done. First part of this class is done. Visualization will take some time. It might take one more class, but for now, this class, I'm giving it a little simple, because all of these concepts are a little…
Monal S: New to all of you.
Monal S: Alright? So let me share the file, and guys, any one of you, please try to put the same thing in the community. Okay?
Monal S: I've sent it. Anyone, please, before going…
Monal S: On your break, please send this on the community.
Monal S: Later, I will send the full thing. How to split date and time, because it is now in the one row.
Monal S: You can split it thumb.
Monal S: Just check the US class, do it.
Monal S: Guys, how many of you will be able to split year, date, month, etc?
Monal S: How many of you can do that?
Monal S: Guys, in this one, I already have a URL. People can say you can… I can.
Monal S: It means others can as well. I'm teaching the same thing to everyone. If anyone will say I can, it means others can also do that. Yes! Pulkit is saying dt.month, dt.year. Correct.
Monal S: If I do… dot DT. year.
Monal S: Okay, this is .dexSR with date-time-like values. What is the value here? Let's see.
Monal S: DF.info.
Monal S: This is not, date time, so to get it, I will use invoice.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: We should know why we're getting error.
Monal S: If I do this.dt.ere, We will guide here. If we do dt.month.
Monal S: Maybe we'll get this. How hard it is.
Monal S: Okay, thank you very much, Dawal. Guys, Dawal has shared the same thing in the community, and whoever has done the same thing, thank you very much. And guys, let's start a timer today.
Monal S: Let's again do 15 minutes, okay? Then we will come back.
Monal S: Thank you guys, thank you for the first half, we'll see you after 15 minutes.
Monal S: Migrants.
Monal S: Otherwise, welcome back.
Monal S: Are we back. What do you guys had for breakfast today?
Monal S: That's good, Adity.
Monal S: Ma, no sir?
Monal S: I pay, and I can't pay.
Monal S: Red omelette.
Monal S: That's good. That is healthy.
Monal S: You had to have Pandit Shalom, what were you doing?
Monal S: We have 15 minutes.
Monal S: Scrambled eggs.
Monal S: Medivhara, it's good.
Monal S: Whey protein. Good, guys, good. Still dawn in West Africa, but Alfred, you might be feeling hungry, right?
Monal S: We don't eat based on time, we eat based on requirement. Water. Someone had water in the breakfast, that's good.
Monal S: Alright, guys.
Monal S: Sir, do you watch cricket? I don't watch cricket, guys.
Monal S: But in the society, I think tournament is going on. That's why you'll be able to hear sometimes people are cheering.
Monal S: For the holiday, you are already checking the… In motion, Rahul.
Monal S: We had already. We have already.
Monal S: Drinking tea to wake me up, Pharaohs. All right.
Monal S: Good, guys, good. Don't worry, I will not stretch this class a lot, because we're already learning a lot of things, alright?
Monal S: So, let's start. Yes, war news. Yep, guys, what is going on?
Monal S: Let's hope for the best.
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: Next, have everyone focus on the screen.
Monal S: And if possible, we will close it, okay? So…
Monal S: Now, we will start our data visualization. Okay, data visualization. And the first library that we'll be using for visualization, this is going to be the main core library, just like NumPy is a library, and others use it.
Monal S: This is one of the libraries which others library are going to use it internally, called as matplotLabel.
Monal S: Okay? It's a powerful 2D plotting library in Python, and it allows you to create publication quality figures in a variety of formats, like PNG, JPEG, PDF, SVG, etc. Okay? Publication quality means if you want… if you are doing research, and if you want to, create a…
Monal S: Visualization, to put into the research, you will be able to add it. Again, everything should be minimalist. Minimalism. It should follow minimalism, okay?
Monal S: And it is commonly used in matplotlib, PyPlot, and we can use it by importing it as a PLT, okay? So, next is, why use Matplotlib? Why use this particular library? Well, this is a core plotting engine behind other fancy libraries like Seabon.
Monal S: And also, Pandas has its own library to plot things. But Pandas also internally uses
Monal S: matplotlib. So this is the main engine, this is the main plotting engine that we are learning, okay? It works natively with directly NumPy and Bandas, and if you check, a few days back, I have shared you my GitHub repo when I was doing the analysis. Yes or no?
Monal S: I shared you one of that, where I was… there, I was using everything with NumPy.
Monal S: And I was plotting it, so I was plotting it with NumPy data on matplotlib.
Monal S: Okay? This particular library gives you low-level control of every visual element, so if you want to make minor changes also, you will be able to do it, because this is the main library in Python. Alright? Are we clear?
Monal S: Now, what we will do, we will import it. Import matplotlib.pyplot as plt. This is where we have Python plots. If I run it, you can see it is not there. What we have to do now.
Monal S: What we have to do now?
Monal S: Correct.
Monal S: Let me check the exact name. The name itself is matplotlib, so what we will do…
Monal S: Let me open the terminal, or we can do one thing that directly add into the pipe project, or just use UVAddmat.lib.
Monal S: It will install… It will download…
Monal S: It will download and then install.
Monal S: Ben?
Monal S: Back.
Monal S: Let's run it now, let's try to import it.
Monal S: Yes, it is working.
Monal S: Okay, next. Next, what I want to do…
Monal S: How many of you here knows GroupBy? This is the first time I am teaching you, so I think a lot of you will not know about Group By.
Monal S: But let me show it, okay?
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: So, here what we have…
Monal S: my problem… let's talk about dataset that we have. Think of data set as I have name, everyone.
Monal S: I have a name column, I have, country column, I have… salary column.
Monal S: Name is A… B… C, B, E, F.
Monal S: India, U.S.
Monal S: Canada… let's say Africa, then US, then let's say France.
Monal S: Alright? Then, let's talk about some salary.
Monal S: just giving random salary. Don't say, I'm US, I need more salary, I'm…
Monal S: Canada, I need more salty, just some random values, okay?
Monal S: Alright? Now, what I want, I want to do group by on country. I will tell you what it does.
Monal S: I want to do group…
Monal S: Group by is an aggregation technique, and it does… it… it groups by things. So, tell me how many unique groups we have.
Monal S: How many unique groups that we have here in country?
Monal S: And country, I have… India?
Monal S: U.S.
Monal S: Canada.
Monal S: Africa, and France.
Monal S: So, I have 5 groups here, alright? How many data I have in total?
Monal S: Total number of rows that I have here.
Monal S: 6… I have 6.
Monal S: 6 arrows.
Monal S: And this is my data frame. This above thing is my data frame. So when I do DF of country, and if I do group by on country, what will happen? My whole data is going to be creating… my whole data is going to get grouped based on the country. So, if I do IND,
Monal S: IND will come here.
Monal S: With a thousand.
Monal S: Okay? Do we have another India? No. Let's talk about B. B is U.S,
Monal S: 2000… do we have another US?
Monal S: E. I have another US 1000.
Monal S: Let's talk about Canada. AVEC is… Canada, 2000 Days Africa.
Monal S: 3,000. Then we have friends.
Monal S: It will create these groups.
Monal S: Let me write groups.
Monal S: This is one group.
Monal S: This is another group. All of them will belong to their respective groups.
Monal S: Are we clear what grouped by does?
Monal S: Are we clear what group buy does?
Monal S: So, now that this is a separate group by, this is a separate group by, I can do group by on country and sum.
Monal S: If I do group by on country, and then some of their salary. So, this one will be 1000, this one will be 3,000, this one will be 2,000. So, I can do group by operations. Once I group it, based on group, I can do further more operations. Are we clear?
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: So, similarly, this is grouped by on single column. Now, the problem statement is, okay? The problem statement is, what I want to do next…
Monal S: What I want to do next, I want to… I want to find…
Monal S: Find… Monthly… revenue.
Monal S: I want to do monthly revenue. That's all I want to do.
Monal S: It means, if I talk about the data frame, which are the following columns I require?
Monal S: Let's talk about the data frame, df.info, df.head of tooth. It's small.
Monal S: What I want, I want revenue, I want monthly revenue.
Monal S: I want to get total monthly revenue. That is my problem statement. What I need to do?
Monal S: I need to group by on month data.
Monal S: I want to group by on-month data, then what I… what do I have to do next? Step 1.
Monal S: Get… monthly revenue.
Monal S: What is step number one?
Monal S: Approved by month.
Monal S: Once I have the group of month, what should I do?
Monal S: Sound there… revenue. Yes?
Monal S: Yes, some not others' revenue, some that group revenue itself.
Monal S: So, to solve it, what I will do, I will use DF,
Monal S: dot group by, guys, I'm not going to explain, I'm teaching it slow.
Monal S: If you're having issue right now, tell me. Don't say at the end, I'm having issue, I don't understand. So, I want to do group by on month.
Monal S: Done. Let's see how the data looks like.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: This is a pandas object, we will not be able to see it here, but if I store it into something called a dummy DF, let's see how it looks like.
Monal S: It is, again, our data frame object. If I do head.
Monal S: See this? This is invoice. This is all the month data.
Monal S: all the month data. This is a different month data. Yes, are we able to see that created 125 rows
Monal S: Guys, are we able to see it created 125 rows?
Monal S: and total number of 10 columns. This is on group buy of month, okay? This is only head.
Monal S: Okay, let's not worry about it. So, we did group by off month, now it created groups internally. What we want to access next is, we want to access their revenue.
Monal S: We want to access their revenue. And what we want to do with that revenue? So this one will give me a particular month and all of their revenues. Are you able to understand? This one will give me a particular month and all its revenue. Similarly.
Monal S: This one will give me… US, and all its salary.
Monal S: So what we are doing? Selecting a particular month, and accessing all the revenue. What we want to do next? Sum.
Monal S: So now if I do sum on this…
Monal S: then I will get all the sum. Next is, I just want to sort the index, because it will have different, different index.
Monal S: Yes, it will have different, different index. I want to sort it. Once I sort it, I will say this is…
Monal S: Monthly, Okay, I've been.
Monal S: Okay, monthly revenue. Done.
Monal S: Let's print it.
Monal S: Are we able to see month-wise revenue?
Monal S: This is December, this revenue.
Monal S: January 2010, this revenue. All the way to 2011, December, this is the revenue. Yes? Good.
Monal S: Simple operation, very fast, and it gives us a lot of information, a lot of… Aggregated information. Aggregated means…
Monal S: From lot of data, we are creating a single entity. So, from lot of revenue, we created a single number. When we do that, that data, we call it as aggregated data. Are we clear what is aggregated data?
Monal S: Guys… Are we clear about this aggregated data?
Monal S: Next, done. Now that we have this data, let's plot a line plot. If you forget what is line plot.
Monal S: This is light blocked.
Monal S: Let's plot a line plot to see, on an increasing month how the revenue looks like.
Monal S: Again?
Monal S: We will do group by on month.
Monal S: So, all the manga data, We will do group by on month.
Monal S: So, it will group by all the month data like this. Now, all the month data has its own rows, just like this. Let's suppose this is month
Monal S: Crew chosen at 9 and 12, this is one row, this is another row.
Monal S: If I do group by on month, this will create a group like this. Now, each of this has a row as well. Each of these has a column of revenue. I am selecting all the revenue, so I will select all the revenue of a particular month. Once I have it, I will do the sum of it, and I will get it.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: FiberTable is also there. Jason.
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: Alright, so now let's start.
Monal S: And before going to the line plot, I wanted to start with the line plot itself, but without this data. Then we will plot this data.
Monal S: I added sort because it has index to it, Yes?
Monal S: This month will have its own index, this month will have its own index. I just want to sort the index so it looks in ascending order. That's why we have sort index.
Monal S: It does not change the data, it just changes how it looks like. Okay?
Monal S: How it will decide the invoice number, which one should show?
Monal S: Guys, is it showing you invoice number, Ankit?
Monal S: I want you to ask, Write your questionnaire and tell me that what are we asking?
Monal S: Is it, is it present in the data on the screen? Guys, are we able to see invoice?
Monal S: I have to draw it, because you will not understand it.
Monal S: This is my invoice stock code. First, when I do group by on month, when I do group by on month.
Monal S: I will have different, different months, and the row will be grouped by. But each of these rows is going to have same number of columns, each of these groups is going to have same number of columns, but all the rows will be… will belong to a particular month.
Monal S: All the rows will belong to a different month, all the rows will belong to a different month. Is this part clear to everyone?
Monal S: Is this part clear to everyone?
Monal S: Now, this is a separate set.
Monal S: In this set, what I want, I only want to focus on revenue. So, I want to focus on revenue. Revenue is one of those columns, how to select only one column.
Monal S: by using a single bracket. If this is giving me group, this is how I can select revenue, yes or no?
Monal S: We have not learned this previously, tell me.
Monal S: This is how we select revenue. Now that we have revenue, which is all numbers, if I do apply the sum method, it will sum only the numbers where we are having a doubt of invoice.
Monal S: Where are we having a doubt of invoice here?
Monal S: Anyone?
Monal S: Guys.
Monal S: Invoice is present in the group, but are we trying to access the invoice?
Monal S: Are we trying to access the invoice?
Monal S: Right?
Monal S: Anyone has doubt here, I can again teach you, but tell me if…
Monal S: you have some doubt, first check what doubt that you have, and see the code. Okay?
Monal S: Guys, see the code.
Monal S: Giving you one minute.
Monal S: Let me know once you're done.
Monal S: Done?
Monal S: Let me remove this.
Monal S: The name itself suggests sort the index.
Monal S: Pipe.
Monal S: Are they?
Monal S: Is your issue is on?
Monal S: Now it's clear. Guys, are we even being developer here right now?
Monal S: Guys, I don't want you to do coding. I want you to just look at the screen and understand the code.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: Alright, thank you. Thank you, guys.
Monal S: Alright.
Monal S: So let's start with line plot, and I will first show you line plot, how to create it using simple pandas, okay?
Monal S: So, what I'm going to do, I am going to use… I'm going to create pd.series. I'm going to use this data, don't worry, I'm going to use this data for plotting, but for now.
Monal S: But for now, what I'm going to do, I'm going to create a dummy data. This time, I'm creating a series.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: To create a series, I will write 100, 200, 150, some kind of a trend I am plotting, and then I need to pass the index. Don't tell me why I want to pass the index.
Monal S: If you don't know this, I would suggest you to please revise all the concepts which we have learned, you know.
Monal S: All from the Python.
Monal S: Q4. Q1, Q2, Q3, Q4, I'm creating a Panda series, and this is my data.
Monal S: And when I plot this data, df.head.
Monal S: we will see all the data. Q1, Q2, Q3, Q4, and we have all this data. As I told you about the matplotlib, matplotlib
Monal S: also works with Pandas plots. So Pandas itself natively provide you few plots when you work with a data type of Pandas itself. Is this data a data type of Pandas? Yes, it is a Pandas data frame.
Monal S: So it provides you few things by default, but we are not going to use it a lot. We are always going to use it matplotlib. But for now, for the simplicity, for this one example, I want to show you, that on this data frame, if you do plot, by default, it is going to use
Monal S: By default, it is going to use the line plot.
Monal S: Alright, it is going to use the line plot. So here, what you're trying… you're telling… you're telling it to plot.
Monal S: it has created all of this plot data, and then you will see this plot. Simple.
Monal S: Is this simple? Using Pandas, it is simple, but we don't use it with Pandas, because it is the matplotlib which provides us low-level control, not the pandas functionality of plot. So here you can see there are a lot of attributes here, but
Monal S: We will talk about that later, okay? We don't have to worry about even pandas block.
Monal S: Serious. Same exact thing, where is that?
Monal S: Okay? So even without this, it works.
Monal S: Now, let's jump to the next part. Okay, we will call our own.
Monal S: So… Yep. Let's start creating the plot from Madplotline.
Monal S: Keep this in mind, that we have used import matplotlib.pyplot as plting.
Monal S: Okay? As PLT. So PLT is the one, if we use it, we'll be able to access matplotlib. So there are multiple steps. Let me write each of the steps, what we need to do before creating a plot. First is, we need to create a canvas.
Monal S: Okay? We need to create a canvas.
Monal S: Using… Width and height.
Monal S: Using width and height parameter.
Monal S: And what we create is in the scale of inches. I know we are working with computers, there is no concept of inches here, but as I've told you, it is used in terms of when you want to print something, it will be in terms of inches, alright? So…
Monal S: inches is there, but we don't have to worry about the scale. All we need to worry about… the first step is to create a blank, empty canvas where we can plot things. Think of it as, like, you want to create an art. The first thing that you will do is, you want to have that empty canvas. Step 1 is to create empty canvas.
Monal S: Step 2… step two is what plot you want to use, okay? What plot you want to use.
Monal S: So… Just wait, yeah.
Monal S: You will decide, I want to plot scatter, or I want to plotline. If you want to just use plotline, you will use plt.plot.
Monal S: PLD.plot is a method which is used for plotline, okay? Others are plot scatter, and others we will see later. This is step number two. Step number three is, now that we have… now that we have, canvas.
Monal S: We have a plot. We will not see the plot right now. There are a few other things which we need to decide for the plot. It… things like, we need to decide the title of the plot.
Monal S: These are optionals.
Monal S: About that.
Monal S: Plot, title of the plot.
Monal S: Then, we also need to provide what is the X label and Y label. In this X label, what is the main title? What this X label means? What this Y label means? What are these numbers? Are these 4 numbers? Are these inches? These are centimeters? What it is. So, we need to provide this. So, first we need to provide is X axis…
Monal S: Labeled.
Monal S: And then, Y axis label.
Monal S: Alright? Then we need to provide this ticks information, okay? We are able to see this ticks. This ticks is on currently 90 degree, it is straight, right? It is… okay, this ticks is 90 degree, okay?
Monal S: We can provide the rotation of the sticks. Do we want 45 degree, 60 degree, 90 degree, whatever it is, we can provide it. So we can provide the direction, but these are optional. For now, I'm just going to write.
Monal S: rotate X labels. So this Q1, which you're able to see, it will also rotate when you provide all of this. Then, what we need to provide? We need to provide
Monal S: Do we want this layout to be fit? So, there are multiple options. If you don't provide fit, it will be a little padded with these empty white spaces. If you provide fit, that will be a little more tight.
Monal S: Alright? So it prevents… when you do fit layout, it prevents… Label clipping.
Monal S: Okay, whatever the levels that is going outside it, it will, it will prevent that from clipping.
Monal S: Next, you need to write whether you want to show the grid or not. Grid means, currently, this one does not have any grid in between, right? But if you want grid, if you want grid in between, grid helps us
Monal S: visualize things like this number is on 200 or 250, it will help us see better. So, you… it is totally up to you whether you want to show grid or not, and once every configuration… there are a lot of configurations, but these are the basic ones. Once these configurations are done, then you need to tell
Monal S: that I want to show… the plot window. Show the plot window.
Monal S: So, the plot window, or we will say… Render the figure.
Monal S: render the figure that we created the canvas for, we added the values, we added all of this information, and once all the information is done, all the configuration are done, render the figure. So, is everyone clear with the steps? Don't worry, I will write the code now, but are we clear with the steps?
Monal S: Create a canvas, then add the data, then add the configurations of those plots, like title, X label, Y label, X rotation, do we want fit or not, do we want to show grid? Once all the configurations are done, let's see the plot.
Monal S: Ananta, I will tell you, it will be more clear when I'm going to run the code, okay? Too many steps, these all are optional.
Monal S: Create a canvas, plot line, and show the plot. That's it.
Monal S: But more configuration means you require more steps.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: Done. Let's start. So let's create a canvas. To create a canvas, we need to write plt.figure.
Monal S: Okay? We need to provide figure size. Figure size. Again, I told you in width and height. First is width. I want 12 inches and 6 inches tall.
Monal S: think of it as, like, just imagine a canvas in your mind that is having 12 inches to 6 inches of figure size. So whatever is… whatever you will see, that is kind of… the main plot will be on that.
Monal S: So, creating canvas is done. Next, what we need to do? We need line chart here. So, let's try line chart. I will do plt.plot.
Monal S: I want a plot, and I need to provide X and Y values. What are the X values of my revenue?
Monal S: What are the X values of this revenue? The index itself. Yes?
Monal S: Index is my X, Y is the value of those index.
Monal S: So, monthly revenue is my series.
Monal S: And if I do monthly revenue.index, I will get all the index. What are the values? Monthlyrevenue.values.
Monal S: This will give me values. Right now, I want marker to be the symbol of hope. There are a different kind of marker, I will talk about it, but these are the markers. These are the markers information.
Monal S: Okay? When we write O, it means you will see a circle in the plot. When you write this dot, you will see a point. When you write this comma, you will see a pixel. When you write plus, you will see plus.
Monal S: I want to see this circle on the graph, that's why I'm saying marker is equals to O.
Monal S: Alright? Pretty simple step. Now that this step is done, let's talk about the title. What title I want this plot
Monal S: I want this plot to have a title of plt.title, monthly revenue over time.
Monal S: This is the title of the plot. Done. Now let's talk about x-axis.
Monal S: What is present in the x-axis? It is the month itself. So my x-axis label I want is label, just the text. I want month to be written there. On the y-axis, what we want. On the y-axis, I want revenue.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: I want revenue to be returned there, so… this is Y-axis.
Monal S: Do we want any rotation? Let's try a rotation of X label to 45 degree. You will see, currently you're able to see that. Then, when I plot it, you will see them in a 45 degree, just a rotation, okay? X ticks, this is a rotation.
Monal S: Once that is done, do we want to fit the layout to prevent the clipping? Yes, let's try it. It will not change much, but it will prevent few things from clipping, that's all. Now, do we want to show the grid? Why not? Let's add grid. I will do plt.grid of true.
Monal S: Now, this is all my configuration. See this? It is still plotting it. It will plot, but if you want to plot once things are done, last thing is pl.show. Run it. Done.
Monal S: Seriously.
Monal S: This will render the final thing. Render the final thing, but all the things you're already adding it to PLT.
Monal S: So, PLT is the main object which has this information, that's why, even without this, you will be able to see it. But if you want to render the final thing, once you are confirmed that I am done adding all the configuration, then add, you can see, display all open figures. Currently, only one figure is open, PLT.
Monal S: So that's why we are able to see only one. You can see, display all open figures. We added this, the title.
Monal S: On the x-axis, we have month, and you can see this 45 degree. All of this ticks test are 45 degree. On the y-axis, Y label, we have revenue, and this is the plot, we are able to see circles. Oh, these are circles. They all are connected.
Monal S: Is everyone clear on the steps? Is it hard?
Monal S: Is it hard?
Monal S: It's not at all hard, guys.
Monal S: It's not at all hard.
Monal S: It is very simple.
Monal S: Interesting. Awesomes.
Monal S: See this?
Monal S: We have VITICS as well.
Monal S: What happens if we don't grip greed? Guys, now, okay, this configuration is clear.
Monal S: This configuration is clear. Now, let's write the same thing, and this time I will say, without grid, so we will know the difference.
Monal S: With AutoGrid, what I will do, I will just comment the grid.
Monal S: This is without grid. Is revenue showing in Y-axis? Is revenue showing in Yocation?
Monal S: You know the number, you can check it later, or Yogesh, you can add it later.
Monal S: Can you explain about layout?
Monal S: Guys, now, let's see without tight layout. Let's see without tight layout.
Monal S: I'm running it again, just see what difference it will make.
Monal S: See this? It got shifted.
Monal S: It got shifted a bit.
Monal S: Okay? So it will not make much of a difference, but when you add this tight layout, you will see all of them. Sometimes it widens it, you will see this, what tight layout does.
Monal S: It pads. Are you able to see? When we add tight layout, it automatically pads some value.
Monal S: Is it padding some values?
Monal S: It pairs some value, that's why you see some space. If you don't use it, that space is now less…
Monal S: It is little compact.
Monal S: Okay? So, totally up to you guys. It is totally up to you. It does not make any error, or it does something. Data is data.
Monal S: Now tell me, people are asking, guys, I want you to… let me zoom in.
Monal S: I want you to see this, and tell me why revenue is not correct. Guys, is revenue correct or not? Tell me. The first thing, is revenue correct or not?
Monal S: Is revenue correct or not?
Monal S: It is correct. See the final number.
Monal S: 1E6.
Monal S: It means whatever that number is, It is exponential.
Monal S: Search on the internet what is 1E6, help me here.
Monal S: Search on internet what is 1E6?
Monal S: Enable in the chat to everyone.
Monal S: Tell me what is 1E6?
Monal S: Divided by 1000, What do you mean by divide by 1000? What is 1E6?
Monal S: 10 to the power of 6.
Monal S: 1 is 6 means 10 to the power of 6, so multiply 1.2 into 1 is 6. Is this the correct number?
Monal S: Is this the correct number?
Monal S: It is incorrect numbers.
Monal S: Alright.
Monal S: So we have seen…
Monal S: We have seen with… in disabling the grid, guys, grid is good or not. For me, personally, I like grids.
Monal S: I like grids. It is helping me, sir, what X rotation does.
Monal S: Guys?
Monal S: See this graph? I am removing the rotation now. See what happens?
Monal S: what happens? The text is good, now it is on 0 degree.
Monal S: Now it is on 0 degree.
Monal S: text is on zero degree, it will overlap, because there is not enough space. When I do X tick of 90, it will be…
Monal S: 90 degree.
Monal S: when I do 45, It will be 45 degree, the text direction.
Monal S: You are the developer, you will decide your plot, how you want to make it look like.
Monal S: Are we clear? Is everyone clear?
Monal S: Alright, let me copy this.
Monal S: And let's jump to the next part.
Monal S: Same graph, I will add grid as well, I will add grid as well, but this time, after figure, this time, I want some kind of a style. It comes with themes.
Monal S: It comes with themes. To use themes after having the canvas, or in between also you can add it, but I'm adding at the very start, so that I know whatever plot is going to be, it is going to be according to that theme.
Monal S: What is the style I'm using? I'm using Classic. Everything else is same. Tight layout is also same. Let's run it.
Monal S: Which one do you like?
Monal S: This one?
Monal S: Or this one.
Monal S: Which one do you guys like?
Monal S: 1 or 2.
Monal S: Both of them are good in their own places, but for me, this one looks more sharp, and the color looks good to me.
Monal S: Both of them has the grid, guys.
Monal S: This one also has the grid, but the grid style also changes. Can you see? The grid style here also changes in the second one.
Monal S: This is a different grid style.
Monal S: You can see revenue also reflecting differently. Because the style is having different configuration, it will change all of things.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Done. Okay? So if you want to talk about different kinds of a style, we have different kinds of styles. If you want to see what are different styles available, you can use plt.style.available.
Monal S: These are all the styles available, you guys can check it.
Monal S: There are lots of styling.
Monal S: See this? Classic? We used Classic.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: If you use ggplot, ggplot is one of the classics one. ggplot is from R library, okay? R is another programming language's, and there we have ggplot.
Monal S: So if I use ggplot in one of the styles, let's see how it looks like.
Monal S: Looks fancy, little fancy.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: If I remove this grid, let's keep the grid, but…
Monal S: Let's suppose I want to remove this tight layout.
Monal S: Then you can see this, guys. Tight layout was making some changes on top of it.
Monal S: But now you can see that weird gray color is not there, but you can see this point is kind of trimming at the end, yes or no?
Monal S: Yes or no? It is getting trimmed a lot, trimmed a bit, but when I do tight layout.
Monal S: It is still trimming, but okay, let's see.
Monal S: But now I'm not getting that gray color because of that engine. Sometimes it adds that value, sometimes it doesn't. Let's remove it. Now it is perfect. At the start, it looks a little weird, but when I add this layout, it gets little zoomed, but I think the value is still a little cut, right?
Monal S: The value is still getting cut a bit.
Monal S: But this one is a little bit more padded. And guys, if you don't know the meaning of padded, say this.
Monal S: if I have this box, if I have this box here.
Monal S: If I have this box, and in this box, I want the contents to be in the same location. I want content to be in the same location. Let me write it with the actual rectangle, okay?
Monal S: This is my rectangle.
Monal S: I want all the points to be present in the same location in the box, but what I want
Monal S: I want this box to be a little bit of… little bit bigger. What I will do, I will pad this box with space. So, I will increase this box width, increase this box width. Let's suppose I want to pad by 5.
Monal S: 5 inch, 5 inch, 5 inch, 5 inch. What will happen? What will happen? The new box is the same as the original box, but now it has more space. Content will still be same, but now it has more space. Are we clear?
Monal S: Are we clear what is padding? This is called as padding.
Monal S: Alright? So when we are doing tight layout, the first argument you will see is pad.
Monal S: whatever the width is, paired with 1.08 times more. It means
Monal S: whatever you will gain from this 0.8, just pad that value. If I do pad with
Monal S: 5. It means whatever the original width is, pair that by multiplying by 4, 4 times.
Monal S: See this? We are padding with 4.
Monal S: Sometimes it is… okay, when I pad with 2, because it needs to change the proportion also, right? When we change the proportion, the size also changes.
Monal S: When I paired with only 0.
Monal S: 7, you can see the space is getting. So, based on the proportion, it will do that, alright?
Monal S: Is everyone clear?
Monal S: Yes, I'm already able to do it later. Okay? Later, one by one.
Monal S: One by one.
Monal S: Fun. Today's class is fun.
Monal S: Seeing the data, how we can know what are the plots we need with data. Guys.
Monal S: I told you the very basic, you don't have to worry about more. This is more than enough. I require bar plot… bar plot when I want to check the comparison. Read about it, you cannot learn in the first day, okay? You cannot learn. I already gave you the intro. These are the actual places where you'll be using it.
Monal S: Don't learn a lot.
Monal S: Okay? Next, what I want is, on these points, guys, on these points, I want to see the actual numbers. I told you in one of the principles that it is better to have numbers. What was that point?
Monal S: Label everything.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Label… everything. So now, let's use label.
Monal S: So before doing that label, let me show you the concept. We will add the label, because I like this graph, okay? I like this graph, we will add the label here.
Monal S: This time, I will say… label.
Monal S: adding… Label on points.
Monal S: This is width grade. I want this width grade.
Monal S: Is this with grid? Grid is true.
Monal S: Style is classic, it is good, we have data.
Monal S: Alright, so what we are doing, we are plotting these markers, these circles on this X and Y. Is this partial to you guys?
Monal S: We are plotting on these markers that will give you X and Y.
Monal S: X and Y.
Monal S: So… I already have X and Y.
Monal S: I already have sets of X and Y.
Monal S: So, if this is my plot.
Monal S: If this is my plot, this is X, this is Y.
Monal S: This is X, this is Y. This is the point, let's say. This is 1, 2, this is 1,
Monal S: 2 is 0.5.4. 1, 1.52, 1, 1.52. Let's suppose the first X and Y is…
Monal S: It means this is 1, this is 2, the intersection is going to be this.
Monal S: Is this point clear to everyone?
Monal S: Is this point clear to everyone? Now, what I want… I want a text, I want something on top of it.
Monal S: What I want, I want label. What exactly I want to print on this graph?
Monal S: what exactly I want to print on top of it? I want to print X, or I want to print Y.
Monal S: I want to print X on this red dot, or I want to print Y.
Monal S: Which one will be better?
Monal S: Which one will be better? Why? Yes?
Monal S: If I can see my revenue on top of this circle, then it will be better. So, what I want, I want Y on top of it. Well, I will tell you how to put Y. You… you don't have… Y is not a part of plt.plot. plt.plot only plots these circles.
Monal S: Anything that you want to add extra on top of your screen, on top of your canvas, you want to add text.
Monal S: you want to add text at a particular location. You want to add text on a particular X and Y. What is the text we want?
Monal S: What is the text we want? We want revenue.
Monal S: We wanted certain X comma Y.
Monal S: Yes, revenue is some number. Let's suppose $120,000 is the revenue. Revenue is some text that we want to plot on this X and Y. Now, if this is a text.
Monal S: And it requires a coordinate of X and Y. Everyone listen. If this is the text, and I want to plot that on top of X comma Y,
Monal S: If this is my XY, I will be starting from… Do you want overlap?
Monal S: Do you want overlap?
Monal S: No.
Monal S: We don't want overlap. It will actually look from this. It will center the text on this accent Y. Now, if I move the text in this direction, what I'm doing, I'm increasing X or Y,
Monal S: If I'm moving the text in this direction, what I'm doing, I'm increasing X or Y,
Monal S: I will do X++. If I, move in this direction, what I will be doing.
Monal S: what I will be doing, X minus minus. If I do in this direction what I will be doing.
Monal S: Tell me!
Monal S: Y minus minus? Because Y is starting from zero. Y is increasing in this part.
Monal S: If I move in this direction, I will do Y++. Yes? So, now, think of, if this is my point, if this is my point, and I want to write on top of it, I already know X, I already know Y.
Monal S: If X is… if X is… let's suppose for this point.
Monal S: For this point, this is X, this is, let's suppose, 1.5, okay?
Monal S: I have X as…
Monal S: 2.5, I have Y as 1.5. What should I do? What should I do in this number to make this text on top of the circle?
Monal S: What should I do?
Monal S: Oh, sorry, you were able to see everyone's chat?
Monal S: What should I do? Should I increase the X, or should I keep the X?
Monal S: My X should be as it is. On my Y, even if I increase it a bit, 1.8, will it go on top?
Monal S: Anything that is more than, more than 1.5, it will go on top.
Monal S: If I increase this a lot, if I make it, like, 3.5, what will happen?
Monal S: I will see 120 on top of it.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: Yes or no?
Monal S: Yes? So the similar concept, we will use it to draw text on top of the canvas. So let's plot it. Everyone, 3.5 will be too much. Yes, correct. So here, what we have, we have the plot. This line is correct. This will plot that circle.
Monal S: Next is, what I will do, I will iterate over my… I will iterate over my revenue values, but I also need index of the revenue for that X
Monal S: Yes, I need X and Y. Index is already present in monthly revenue. Here, I have values. So what I will do, for I, comma, value N,
Monal S: Enumerate of monthly revenue.values, If I iterate over it, can I get both X and Y in this iteration?
Monal S: If I do monthly revenue.index of i, this is my X,
Monal S: And if I do monthlyrevenue.values of i, This is what?
Monal S: This is what… my value, but I already have value here, I'm already recreating over it.
Monal S: I'm already iterating over it. So I can replace this with this.
Monal S: This is my X, this is my Y.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Now, based on the graph, if we see the graph, we can see that little bit on top of any value. Currently, all of these values are in thousands of value, yes?
Monal S: All of these values are in thousands of this value. This is 700,000, this is 800,000. So, distance between that is 700,000 to 800,000.
Monal S: So, if I add in value, if I add one value, will it make any difference?
Monal S: Will it make any difference in the plot?
Monal S: No. Even if I do 100, will it make any difference?
Monal S: If my distance between these bigger values is 100,000, Difference itself is 100,000, so…
Monal S: If I add $100,000, it will be too much. Yes or no?
Monal S: If I add 100,000, it will be too much of a difference. So, let's remove one zero here, for now. We're just testing it. This is for testing. So this is my coordinate of X and Y. Part clear.
Monal S: This is my coordinate of X and Y. I will write, using this particular method, I can write text on my plot.
Monal S: the same plot, I can write text. This is my X and Y. Did we mention anywhere what we want to write?
Monal S: Did we mention anywhere what you want to write? No.
Monal S: Third argument is, we provide the string what we want to write on top of this X comma Y.
Monal S: So I will write F string, okay? I will write F string, and here I will provide integer of the value. I don't want to provide decimals. It's totally up to you. I am choosing to not show the floating point. I'm only choosing this, okay?
Monal S: and value, and then what I want?
Monal S: This is horizontal alignment.
Monal S: Do you want…
Monal S: Do you want text to be at the center of the circle, or on the right, on the left?
Monal S: This is the center. Do you want it to be present?
Monal S: here or here. We want it at the center. So, we are saying that what should be the horizontal alignment? I want center. So, I will say H as center.
Monal S: Okay? And because it's a text, it's a text, it should have its own font size.
Monal S: It should have a font, right? Otherwise, you can say font size of 40. It will not make sense. It will be too big. So, I want font size of 8.
Monal S: Alright, let's run it.
Monal S: Is it hard, guys?
Monal S: it will iterate over all the values and put text into the canvas. Then we have other things, then we have other things, finally it will render it.
Monal S: Finally, it will render it.
Monal S: HA Center is horizontal alignment.
Monal S: This is my horizontal line. This is my horizontal line.
Monal S: in this line, where I want my new text to be aligned.
Monal S: Do I want to align it to the right? Do I want it to align to the right left? Do I want to align to the center?
Monal S: Are we clear, Harsh?
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: So, guys…
Monal S: I know a lot of you are a little confused. Few of you are confused. I want you to read what this value is doing. Everyone. What is X, what is Y? Read these two lines of code. I'm giving you two minutes.
Monal S: Giving you 2 minutes. Chat is disabled.
Monal S: I think 2 minutes is pretty long for this small statement.
Monal S: Are we able to understand? This index, this X value, is nothing but
Monal S: These values that we were creating here.
Monal S: Where is our actual data frame? These are X values.
Monal S: on the plot.
Monal S: And using this, we were getting these values.
Monal S: This is our X… This is our Y, this is our X,
Monal S: Are we clear now on X and Y?
Monal S: And we can get on X and Y.
Monal S: See, text has a lot of things, but for now, we are providing X and Y. Guys, text you will see in computer vision and everything. This text will remain same.
Monal S: In loop, in for loop, can't we use directly i? Guys, we can use it, but I'm… I already have a value.
Monal S: value, I already have it here from the enumerate, then I already have it, I'm using it for index.
Monal S: Okay? Done.
Monal S: Let's run it and see the answer.
Monal S: Is this better?
Monal S: Good?
Monal S: Guess?
Monal S: That's great love, Kesh.
Monal S: Axelair?
Monal S: Looks professional.
Monal S: What text we will show, and where we have written.
Monal S: This is the location of where? X comma Y. This is X…
Monal S: This is why… what text we want to return is the third argument.
Monal S: Center alignment is the fourth argument, font size is the fifth. Neha, are we clear?
Monal S: Looking very nice.
Monal S: Okay? How to make the text bold, I will teach you all of that. Okay? I will teach you all of that. Okay.
Monal S: Cropping values left and right, guys, if it is cropping value, because it is cropping, because the value itself is very dense.
Monal S: Okay? Value itself is very dense. You can add a series of 0 and 0 in the NumPy, or…
Monal S: See, because point itself is very small.
Monal S: Okay, point itself is very small. The chart itself is very large in terms of the scale.
Monal S: Disable that check.
Monal S: Okay? So guys, everything will get practi- will be cleared with practice, trust me. Now.
Monal S: One good question is, sir, what should I do to make this text bold?
Monal S: So, there is another way. See this? This text is here, you can provide different configuration here, but Matplotlib tells us that I can provide you a better way for the configuration. If you check on the text, you will see font dict. Yes.
Monal S: If you click on it, you will see it is accepting some kind of a font dict here. We can provide that font red dict as well. So I will show you how to provide that font redict. So let me copy the whole thing.
Monal S: And I will say… using… Fond deck.
Monal S: And fontict is, argument, it is about font, it should be present in the text. Don't use fontict here, it will not make sense.
Monal S: It is an argument of text, and this is text. So let's create a font. What I want, I want to create a dictionary. Dictionary name can be anything. I want to say font family.
Monal S: I'm hoping everyone knows what is a font family. Everyone is using Microsoft Word, Google Sheet, everything. It is a family of the font, okay? I'm using Serif. Serif is the font family I want to use. I want to use font color. Let's provide the color as black. I can use black.
Monal S: And I want weight. Weight is where we can pass bold and other things. I want bold.
Monal S: I want weight to be bold. I want size of the font. Size of the font, I want to be 10.
Monal S: When I'm already passing the font size, do I need to pass the font size here?
Monal S: color… no, I should not be passing the font color here. Okay, see, I'm not passing it, but font size, I should not be passing. Let me remove the font size.
Monal S: Okay? Font size I'm removing. And here, in font addict, I will pass the dictionary which I created.
Monal S: So, using this configuration, now I can control the text. If I run it.
Monal S: Is it pulled now? See, again, this mat lotly sometimes creates this weird gray. If I run it again.
Monal S: Or, let me disable the tight layout and enable it again.
Monal S: Okay, it is working a little weirdly.
Monal S: So, let me check what else we can do here.
Monal S: Hmm.
Monal S: Weird in general.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: How to remove this gray, weird thing?
Monal S: There is no configuration that is adding this gray thing, but let me check, guys, why we are getting this weird error.
Monal S: Okay? Let me write one thing, let me overwrite something, just wait.
Monal S: In the figure, there is one argument, let's see if it works or not.
Monal S: Okay, it works, okay? So it was messing with that value, so in figure in the canvas, while we are creating the canvas, if we specifically pass face color equals to white, it will always be white. It will not work this weirdly, alright? But apart from that, is everything clear?
Monal S: Is everything clear?
Monal S: Guys?
Monal S: If I add a different color, I want font to be orange.
Monal S: These are base colors, that's why you can write the name. Font color will be orange, okay? But here, see this? You are providing a font dictionary, but you can also write a font color here as well. Let's see which one is having the higher priority.
Monal S: Let's see which one is having the higher priority. If we write color in plt.text, and let's say I'm saying black, let's see which one is having the higher priority. Font dictionary, or the argument of font. Are we able to understand what I'm trying to say, guys?
Monal S: Are we able to understand what I'm trying to say? Which one is having the higher priority?
Monal S: Which one is having the higher priority?
Monal S: Argument of the color itself.
Monal S: Alright? So don't be confused.
Monal S: I am making it in a single place for now, and I think orange looks very weird. So black is fine. Okay?
Monal S: Black is fine.
Monal S: One thing which we can also do in the plot itself, plot also has a property of color. So, if I write color, and if I write, let's say, green.
Monal S: It will be green.
Monal S: Are we clear?
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: I'm done.
Monal S: How can we rotate the value? In the text? I'm not sure if…
Monal S: we have any degree here in the text. I cannot see any degree, it is only having X, Y, font, dictionary, and all of it.
Monal S: So… There's some GC I need to check.
Monal S: In this GCA, do we have any other figure?
Monal S: We can check, guys, okay? You can check the configuration in the official documentation, what these guys provide. Yes, Dharani, it is possible.
Monal S: Okay, a different value, when you put it, it is possible.
Monal S: Alright, I see one next thing.
Monal S: Said too much over here, actually? Okay, Karan, don't fail. Guys, let's see this next part. Only next part.
Monal S: Plotting… multiple… values in, single plot.
Monal S: I don't have… guys, do we have two different revenue values?
Monal S: Do we have two different revenue values? Tell me.
Monal S: Ramesh using this.
Monal S: I don't have two different values. So what I'm going to do, I am going to copy this first part, this part, two times.
Monal S: This one is plotting.
Monal S: the first… line… The first line plot.
Monal S: Tell me, what can I do to make two graphs in the same plot?
Monal S: If this is my plot, can I add, in revenues, can I add this value?
Monal S: Keeping the same index.
Monal S: If I keep the same index in the same month, I will see a different value.
Monal S: Yes?
Monal S: I will see a different value.
Monal S: Can I make this color as a different color? Let's not make any color. By default, whatever it is, I will use it.
Monal S: Same thing I have to do herein.
Monal S: value, but this is X comma Y, so I should choose… To write it here.
Monal S: I should not change X comma Y.
Monal S: I should only change this value. Okay, this value is also there, I think we need to change it here as well. Because value is also changing, right?
Monal S: So now, this value… Plus this, this value, plus this.
Monal S: Is everyone able to understand what I just did?
Monal S: Guys, are you able to understand what I just did?
Monal S: This is plot 1, this is plot 2, everything is just values, X comma Y. This is second line plot.
Monal S: Let's see if it works or not.
Monal S: Is it working?
Monal S: Great.
Monal S: This looks good. See, once we understand the basic of plot, a lot of people, what it does, they start some course, they start matplotlib does it, and they don't know how to configure things. But once you understand how plot is working, everything is simple.
Monal S: Make sense?
Monal S: Clear?
Monal S: Clear.
Monal S: Alright?
Monal S: Are you guys tired?
Monal S: Guys, feeling tired?
Monal S: Guys, why index will overchange? We have the same exact index. We have the same exact index. Indexed overlapping, the plotting is…
Monal S: Same, right?
Monal S: Plotting is the same.
Monal S: Okay, I will only do final plot, final plot, and then we will close. Only final plot, I will not explain it much.
Monal S: See this? Next thing I want to do is, I want to show top 10 revenue-generating countries.
Monal S: What I'm trying to do here, is it a comparison, or I just want to see data?
Monal S: Is it a comparison, or is it just plotting data? It is a comparison, I want to see top 10.
Monal S: I should be able to see it. So what I will do, you will know this code, I'm not going to explain it again. I am doing df.groupIOFCountry, revenue sum, I am sorting the values in ascending order.
Monal S: Ascending or not… in descending order.
Monal S: I am sorting the value in descending order, and I'm only taking the first 10 rows.
Monal S: So this will give us only the first 10 rows of this particular group by sum.
Monal S: And I'm saving it to country revenue. If I show you this country revenue series.
Monal S: Are we clear what we just did?
Monal S: Guys?
Monal S: Now, what I will do… simple steps, very simple steps.
Monal S: I will create a canvas.
Monal S: I will now use plt.bar, not PLT.plot. PLT.plot is for line chart. This one is for bar. I provided the index and the value, and I told what is the color of the bar.
Monal S: Next is, very simple things. I want customizations. So let me write customizations.
Monal S: Title, X label, Y label, X tick, title layout, grid. I only want grid in Y-axis.
Monal S: I only want grid in Y-axis.
Monal S: This is one of the configuration. Once customization is done, render it.
Monal S: Is this hard?
Monal S: Same thing we did, but now we want… our problem statement is different.
Monal S: Bone.
Monal S: To remove this weird gray thing which is coming in my system, it might not come in my system, what we should do?
Monal S: What we should do? Add this statement.
Monal S: face color, Add the statement of face color in our system.
Monal S: Yeah, in our canvas.
Monal S: Looks good.
Monal S: And if I use a different style, it will look more good.
Monal S: After Canvas, let's define the style.
Monal S: Looks beautiful.
Monal S: Good.
Monal S: Okay? I think, see, when we see X is equals to Y, guys, we have seen what X is Y was.
Monal S: Keeping the column constant.
Monal S: And all the values, if I show you X, it will be in this direction. X direction, that was in Y direction.
Monal S: Done. This is the last topic of today's class. Done.
Monal S: Clear.
Monal S: Watch today's class fast, guys.
Monal S: Yes, PLT renders, guys. Yes, PLT works on a render basis. You add something to the canvas, then you plot it.
Monal S: So, if you're plotting it, it is not changing the previous thing, because we already plotted it.
Monal S: Towards the end, what is towards the end?
Monal S: It seems UK is an outplayer.
Monal S: In this case, yes, UK is not, but maybe that vendor it's from… that business itself is from UK.
Monal S: Okay? See this scale that is automatically picking if you don't provide it. So for now, guys, let's not add any more detail, okay?
Monal S: Class is a little fast forward towards the end. Guys, if I have… if I taught you this particular thing, why should I be… why should I be teaching you this again?
Monal S: You should understand why I'm doing it. When it was required for me to teach you slow… was it not slow?
Monal S: Was this not slow, the very first graph?
Monal S: This one?
Monal S: I told you step-by-step what we should do.
Monal S: Then I copy and pasted, changed one configuration, then did it again. We only wa- we were only changing one configuration and did it again.
Monal S: Alright? Done.
Monal S: So, you only need to practice, okay? Practice part cannot be done in the class. So, guys, I am starting a poll, poll I am raising, and one thing I also, guys, don't leave the class, I have one thing to share. It's not a surprise.
Monal S: But, one thing, just wait, okay?
Monal S: Fill the feedback, and I will share that part.
Monal S: Stay for 2 more minutes.
Monal S: Are the classes on time?
Monal S: In the meantime, let me… Zip everything that we did.
Monal S: Don't leave yet, please.
Monal S: Level 2, 1st of March.
Monal S: Almost done.
Monal S: Okay, where is our group?
Monal S: Project?
Monal S: End.
Monal S: Copy. Got it.
Monal S: Everyone, I am sharing one link in the chat.
Monal S: What is going on? Okay, let me click on it.
Monal S: I'm sharing one link.
Monal S: And please try to fill it, please try to provide your name, email, contact, select course, and this is, official rating of this course, what I'm teaching. In every course, we do it.
Monal S: In different parts of it, it will also happen in Ultimate Data Science Batch 1.
Monal S: for the second time, this is for you. So please write the feedback for the course, provide my rating, provide my teaching addressing your doubts, and how the LMS is. It is also having option how friendly the LMS is.
Monal S: And, would you recommend this course to others who will join it? Contact number, provide all of this. What course you have. All right, everyone!
Monal S: Are we… do you guys…
Monal S: Have any dot on this? Are you able to access it? How many of you are able to access the link? Click on the link.
Monal S: Is link working? Alright, yes. Please fill it.
Monal S: Not today's class, guys, don't fill the feedback for today's class, it is about the scores.
Monal S: About the course. I know some people will say, matplotlib class was too difficult, I want to change the mentor. There is always those people who will say that.
Monal S: But it is not about today's class.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Thank you.
Monal S: And let me end the poll.
Monal S: Feel tense.
Monal S: Getting exception.
Monal S: What exception we are getting?
Monal S: Can't submit the form? Guys, you're not able to submit the form?
Monal S: What is going on?
Monal S: Permission denied.
Monal S: Okay, maybe we will do it in the next class. Alright, guys?
Monal S: We will do it in the next class, is that fine? Okay, thank you, thank you for at least trying. I will send it again in the next class. This is with Teams, so I don't have the access to it. Alright, guys, thank you.
Monal S: For people, I think they… it works with some people. Guys, are you working with egogrenadotype or something?
Monal S: Not sure how it works for one person.
Monal S: Maybe you need to sign into the Google and then work with it.
Monal S: Alright, we can, we can change.
Monal S: Some people are able to do it, guys. It works for them.
Monal S: Not sure what is the issue.
Monal S: But… Guys, what browser you are using?
Monal S: Guys, what browser you're using, people who are able to do it. People who are able to do it.
Monal S: Chrome. They are using Chrome, guys. Some are saying Chrome working.
Monal S: Edge… It should not be a browser thing.
Monal S: But, okay.
Monal S: Maybe I will share the link again in the next class, and then we will see, okay?
Monal S: Thank you for at least trying, guys, thank you. Let's leave it, okay? Let's leave it.
Monal S: It's a login issue or something. Okay, we will check, guys, we will check.
Monal S: Alright guys, thank you, thank you for trying. In the meantime, let me upload all the files, so that…
Monal S: We can close this session soon as well.
Monal S: Thank you very much, guys, thank you, and please…
Monal S: Practice things a lot, and yes, we have a weekend, we have a holiday, not weekend, we have a holiday.
Monal S: And use your holiday, To whatever you're liking.
Monal S: Learning is not always good, we should always give ourselves some time.
Monal S: That is what I will suggest.
Monal S: But, if you come, like.
Monal S: Thank you, guys, thank you.
Monal S: Thanks a lot, guys. Thank you. Wednesday, we have a holiday, guys. Wednesday, we have a holiday.
Monal S: Okay?
Monal S: Guys, you can leave, yes.
Monal S: Class is over, you can leave.
Monal S: By mistake, I'm uploading two items.
Monal S: It's a global Chrome issue.
Monal S: Let me do it here.
Monal S: Because it is 43MB, that's why it is taking a little bit of time, but in the meantime, let me write other things that we need to check. And guys, if someone asks in the class, please tell them that there is
Monal S: Holiday, okay? Festival holiday is there.
Monal S: Today, we started with data, visualization.
Monal S: Same thing, I will update on the Notion.
Monal S: Here is our notion.
Monal S: Data science done.
Monal S: And guys, only if you have doubt, because I know a lot of you don't even try.
Monal S: Majority of you don't even try.
Monal S: Very few in this class people try.
Monal S: Very few.
Monal S: Let me double-check the resource. Guys, in Notion, I've updated the resource.
Monal S: It is a little large, around 43MB, but everything is there. Today's PDF, notebook, and the file is also there. Alright? Let me also share the same in the chat.
Monal S: In the community chat.
Monal S: Also, one doubt, what is that doubt?
Monal S: How do I remember these things in the matplot? Rahul, practice it.
Monal S: If you say, I can't remember something, let me look at this a lot.
Monal S: I joined this course yesterday, I'm currently working as an associate AI developer at MNC, I'm working on DevOps Cloud, so that's great.
Monal S: I want to start from scratch. I went to some of the videos of Chris and understood that this course is targeted for fresher students. Fresher on any… anyone who is… who wants to start their career in data science, okay? So, how to start the journey? Udayan, or Budyan?
Monal S: you should start watching recordings. There is no other shortcut, okay?
Monal S: Complete all the previous recording, catch up to this class.
Monal S: But don't join live, if you have not watched the previous recordings. Putin, are we clear? So try to complete it as soon as possible.
Monal S: But if you join it here, you are going to waste your time, because you have to watch the previous classes, and you have to watch these classes as well, right? It is going to create unnecessary
Monal S: Where is the final?
Monal S: 0103… Yeah.
Monal S: Thank you guys. Thank you, Pandit Salvam, Dave, and others who…
Monal S: is helping me on putting things on the community. We have holiday on Wednesday. And guys, the resource is also provided in the community, please check it. And guys, if you're not able to submit the form, leave it for now. In the next week, I will again arrange the form, alright?
Monal S: Leave it, leave it for now, alright?
Monal S: Thank you very much, guys. Thank you. File is being uploaded in the community. We'll see you next weekend. Alright? Thank you, guys, thank you. Bye-bye. Only people who have doubled.
Monal S: Next time.
Monal S: Sign.
Monal S: Sign? Deja?
Monal S: Harika, right?
Monal S: PLT.show just renders it, okay? If something gets out from the… that's why that is the last step. We want it to render all the things that we have provided to the PIT, and render it as last. That's what it means. Signage, are you there?
Monal S: which community, how Texas community? Mahesh?
Monal S: go to learn.krishnakrishnakacademy.com. There, you will find your own class resources. Not resources, your recordings. I have provided you the messages. In this section, you will provide messages.
Monal S: In courses section, Meish, are you new to the class?
Monal S: Not sure what is going on with sign, but hey, hey, friends!
Monal S: Depends?
Priince: I hate.
Monal S: Paid links, yes.
Priince: So today in the class, you told that we don't need to remember the syntax, but, just understand the code.
Monal S: Yes, don't… yes, yes, it's fine, it's fine.
Priince: So, at least we can use that…
Monal S: I will kind of remember it.
Priince: Yeah, it means we can use ChatGPT to, follow the… to find the syntax about that code. So, I was having a doubt, like, in an interview… live interview, we can use.
Monal S: Is it CPT or any, or not?
Monal S: that depends totally on the interval, but in the interval, they will not say to Matt Plotly. They will ask you a question on the stats, they will ask you a question on object-oriented programming, they will not go and ask
Monal S: do this in NumPy. They might tell you in Pandas, create a data frame, simple, simple things, but in interview, everyone understands that we are not supposed to remember all of this.
Priince: Okay. Yeah, it means with practice we can remember, but it takes…
Monal S: remember at least high-level things, okay? But it should not be like, if someone is asking you to start Claude, you will say, import NumPy as MP. They will know you don't even know that, right?
Priince: Okay, nice, it was a nice session. Thank you.
Monal S: Goodbye.
Monal S: Alright, Amin, you're next.
Monal S: Amit?
Monal S: Madhan, I will help you.
Monal S: In the meantime, Madhan and everyone who's new to this course.
Monal S: I'm telling you… see, all of this has already been shared in the first class, but I think if you haven't seen the first class, you should go to learn.krishnaacademy.com. This is where you will see your course messages, course resources, and here you will see courses and messages, okay?
Monal S: This is your message section. If you click on message, and it will show you your, batch. I have access to all, you will only have access to your batch. 2.0 is your batch. If you click on it, you will see latest messages here, alright? I have sent the resource here as well, but this is not where you should be looking at the resource.
Monal S: This is where just your chat is. You can talk to your peers. Next is courses. You should search for your course. You should…
Monal S: For me, I have all the access, but you should be able to see your 2.0.
Monal S: If you click on it, you should see a screen like this. Here, you have three sections. Get Started, Miscellaneous, Live Session.
Monal S: Live session is where you will be able to find all of your class… live class recordings, okay? This is where your all live class recordings are, and if you want to check the resource of that live class recording, click on that live class recording, and here you will find resource. This is a resource section.
Monal S: In this resource section, you will find Zip. Zip contains all the things in my handwriting notes, my handwritten notes, my notebook files, and everything, what I'm providing.
Monal S: Okay, that is present in the resource section. And if you want to check,
Monal S: If you want to do fast track of this course using Krishna's YouTube video, you can check in the Get Started, it is Python Detailed Playlist. We have Machine Learning in 6 hours, so these are quick, short versions of the actual thing.
Monal S: So if you quickly want to complete things, check it. If you feel like you have some doubt in some other topic, then you can go to the live session and watch it, for people who jointly sent you, okay?
Monal S: Next is there is Miscellaneous section. In Miscellaneous, you will only see Mentor One Preference. If you click on it, you will find one link at the center of the screen. If you click on this link, you can open it to any place, right? And you will see
Monal S: KN Data Science 2.0. Before even clicking anything on this page, I want you to read each and everything that is written here. Then click on view of the announcement series. If I click on the announcement here, I will see the announcement. Upcoming holiday, 4th March, Wednesday.
Monal S: Do we have any cool Udemy course coupon link? Any upcoming class agenda? This is behind us. I rarely update this, but here you will be able to find
Monal S: what are the basic analysis? This is my GitHub link. This is… if you want… if you're looking for hardware, if you want to buy a laptop, this is my recommendation in the LinkedIn post. If you want to check the AI roadmap, this is present here.
Monal S: So, go through all of this, but…
Monal S: Before reading, this statement, don't click anywhere, or anywhere on this link, alright?
Monal S: Alright, bam.
Monal S: So this is how you should navigate to this course. Are we clear?
Monal S: Yes, Amit, it was your chance, you're still… you still have access.
Monal S: Is everyone clear? Others who joined the schools recently?
amit: Okay, am I audible?
Monal S: Yes, I'm…
amit: Okay, Monasa, like, for the N… for the NumPy, or for the pandas, right? So, I understand that we… we would not be able to remember each and every transformations that we are doing, right? So, we will go as per the flow.
amit: But for plotting, also, do we have to follow the same approach? Like, you should know how the plotting is done.
Monal S: XY alteration, and all those beautifications. Yes, you should know. See, not always you have to do these configurations on the plotting. You can just plot a simple thing, but plotting simple things is only three lines of code. Create a canvas, pass the data, and then pl.stroke.
Monal S: Now, if we want to do the title, X ticks, X title, Y title, those are configurations. Excel plotting is only two lines of code, PAT.show is just to render it, right? That's it.
amit: So all I was, like, wanting to ask is, like, we can use ChatGPT now to get all the information to beautify it.
amit: So we don't need to remember each and every indentation stuff that we are using.
Monal S: ChatGPT gives you something and you want to update on it, you should at least know what I'm trying to do. Just like I was telling you, right? X and Y, you want to write some text on top of it. If you don't know the context of, I'm writing a text, and what is the XY coordinate? If you don't even know that ChatGPT will give you something, it will work, but you never know how to update it.
amit: Got it. Got it.
Monal S: diplom.
amit: Thank you. Yeah, yeah.
Monal S: Yes, you're welcome.
Monal S: Alright, sahed?
Monal S: Hey, Syed.
Monal S: Right?
Monal S: Alright, Santosh is… Alright, yes, Sahid is here. Hey, Sahid.
Sahed: Yeah, hi. Sorry, yesterday it, actually, we are.
Monal S: Yeah, something happened to your system. You were logged off, yeah?
Sahed: Yes.
Monal S: Okay, Said, your issue might take little time. I have 2-3 more people, then I will take your issue.
Sahed: Sure, sure, no issue.
Monal S: Thank you, thank you.
Monal S: Saint is called. Santosh, you're next.
SANTOSH: Yeah, so Mona, with respect to the plotting that you described, right, your first point was picking up the right scale. So, when you say 12, 6 height and width and other things, right, because the data you are loading is more, so how do you pick up that.
Monal S: No, see, that is such a canvas, if you think about it. If you think that your columns are more, and your data is less, if you want to fit more columns, and if you want to see a plot little spaced out, if you want to see data pointed to a spaced out, you will pick a better width, right?
Monal S: If you think that I only have 2-3 columns, and it is fine without a rectangle, you can plot a square. If you see 6, 6, it will be a square.
Monal S: Are you getting my point? If you think you want your data points to have a better height, you will increase the height part and keep the width low.
SANTOSH: So it's up to us in…
Monal S: Yeah, it's up to us.
SANTOSH: And one final question, maybe you would have already repeated it, but I want to confirm it. Like, reporting-wise, I see, like, Plot, Math, PlotLabs, Seabourn, other charts are excellent and looking great, but we cannot share them with the business people. So, ultimately, Power BI and Tableau and other tools are great for business people, and this is for our developers only to understand, like, how the data looks.
SANTOSH: That's what, you confirmed, right? For the plots that we…
Monal S: No, no, can you please repeat that question?
SANTOSH: What I'm trying to say is, yeah, what I'm trying to say is the charts that we prepare, the fancy charts, we cannot show this to our business people, right? Because they, that may not…
Monal S: Show it. See, if that chart is really helpful, you can show it. But most of this fancy chart, which is not a part of this base chart package, right, bar, plot, and those, those are a little difficult. But if they are good, you can feel free to use it. It is totally fine.
Monal S: So, in short, are you saying, like, we can replace Power BI and other costly tools with…
Monal S: That is different. Power BI, you can deploy, your business people will be able to access it, click on it, interact on it. That is a different thing.
SANTOSH: Okay.
Monal S: It's analytics.
SANTOSH: Interactive.
Monal S: Yeah, it is interactive. Interactive also, we have… we have interactive plots, but business people are not going to run code cell by cell, right?
SANTOSH: But it's not the case.
Monal S: in Python as well, but that will not replace Power BI, okay?
SANTOSH: Got it, got it, thank you, thank you.
Monal S: Sure, thank you.
Monal S: Then, we have Podian. Potian?
Monal S: Again?
Udayan Gupta: Yes. Hi.
Monal S: Hey, yes.
Udayan Gupta: Yeah, hi.
Udayan Gupta: So, yeah, so, like I said, like, I have joined the course just yesterday, okay, and I've gone through… Yeah, yeah, and, yeah, hi. So, I have gone through the few recordings as well, and I've… and I've installed… so, I have installed the VS Code and the UV package manager, so that part is done, and we have to start with the recordings of the
Udayan Gupta: Python programming. Yeah. Okay, and I just wanted to know more from your end, like, so if I have any doubts in the previous recordings, should I ask in the community chat? Like, if I don't get asked…
Monal S: Ask in the community. Yes, yes, ask in the community, because community, a lot of people are active, and if they will not be able to even answer, then I will… I will join in, okay? But still, if you have doubt, and we have classes coming, that is Saturday and Sunday, feel free to ask me here.
Udayan Gupta: I can join the… so… so I can join in this last hour, right, and ask the questions for any.
Monal S: previous recordings? Yes. Okay.
Udayan Gupta: Okay, yeah, yeah, thank you so much, thank you, thank you, Munar. And also, one more thing I just wanted to ask you, like, I also noticed that one more course is upcoming, like, regarding the end-to-end, the, like, right, like, for the
Udayan Gupta: projects part, AI projects, so… It's different, it's a different…
Monal S: So, it's a different product formation academy altogether.
Udayan Gupta: I just wanted to know, like, what should be your recommendations? Like, should I complete this course fully, and then start it, or…
Monal S: will be that, once we complete machine learning and deep learning, you can, if you want, you can buy that particular product. There, you have machine learning projects as well, okay?
Monal S: And in the meantime, we'll be completing deep learning Python. There, we have more projects, right? So, once you complete a topic, maybe look out, look some projects, if it is available there, Agentic, and others, because in this course, you are also completing agentic, right?
Udayan Gupta: Yeah.
Monal S: And based on it, you can check it, but if you think that the duration will be too short, I'm not sure whether the product is for 1 year or 1.5 year, I'm not sure. So, accordingly, you should plan it, because you are not paying for 3 years. There, you're only paying for 1 year.
Monal S: So, either
Monal S: You can start from the machine learning, or if you feel like it will be too less of a project for me to complete in one year, maybe buy at the end of the course.
Monal S: It's totally up to you, yes? Okay.
Udayan Gupta: Yeah, okay, okay. Thank you, thank you so much.
Monal S: Thank you, thank you.
Monal S: Okay, I understand. And then we have Mahesh. Mahesh?
Mahesh M: Yeah, I'm on the line, what are you able to do?
Monal S: Amish, yes, you're already nice.
Mahesh M: Actually, what I want to, share about my experience? Actually, two years back ago, I have an interest, developed interest in machine learning. A very small task I have done, which is OCR, reading the PANCAD data, for my organization. We are performing the KYC.
Mahesh M: But after that, I started learning, like, machine learning, like NumPy, Panda, but thing is that whenever I, reach towards the, linear regression, logic regression testing, I don't know, but suddenly, actually, I'm from a web development background.
Mahesh M: So, our… our development is, like, straightforward operation, hardly any, difficult.
Monal S: No concern.
Mahesh M: But in machine learning now, so much theoretically, things are getting involved, like mean mode and in,
Monal S: I'm not coding.
Mahesh M: But actually, apart from that, like, statistics and this thing, so that time…
Mahesh M: My energy gets, weed down, so, like, any…
Monal S: Because you're not able to understand it clearly, once you have a good understanding, and you want to use it in the machine learning, you will not
Monal S: You face an issue.
Mahesh M: But, any suggestion from you to run, learn this thing so that, like…
Monal S: you… see, you're asking me for the question when you have enrolled in this course, okay? When I'm going to teach you that you will get clarity on that, and if you want to do the faster, you can watch the background recordings, Mahesh.
Mahesh M: Oop.
Monal S: Okay?
Mahesh M: Oh, you can watch the batchment recordings if you want to do fast track. Batchman recording machine learning is already completed.
Monal S: But, you should also understand statistics before machine learning. Okay?
Mahesh M: Okay, okay, okay.
Monal S: Okay, don't worry, it is… it is… you… you will not face an issue when to… I know, people, like, when we don't get a clarity of when to use main median mode, what this number means, machine learning feels tough. It all feels conceptual, but when you understand all of these things, it will all make sense, Mesh, okay?
Mahesh M: Okay.
Monal S: Yeah, you're welcome.
Monal S: Alright, so, Syed, I'm going to look into your query now, because Nitin raised hand after everything else is done.
Monal S: Okay, Saeed, I am promoting it to a panelist. Nathan, if you can wait, please wait, okay? We'll solve your query after Saeed's query is done. Said, what I will do, I'm not sure whether it is an issue with VS Code or something. I just… because your system is Windows 10, okay? Windows 10 is all…
Monal S: That is, that is. When are you going to upgrade the Windows? Because you're going to see a lot of software issues later as well.
Monal S: Any plan on upgrading the windows?
Sahed: Yeah, if that is the case, then I can, like, think of doing upgradation again.
Monal S: See, because in my systems, when I was working with Windows 10 at that time, okay, a lot of people were getting Anaconda prompt, VS Code, they were able to recognize the Python, but mine was always working in some kind of a terminal. That is a weird…
Monal S: But I… my first suggestion will be, because if you want to use always the latest of any software, first upgrade the OS itself.
Monal S: We are not sure whether… which of the following packages will not be compatible or working weirdly with your system.
Sahed: Okay? So it is better for the future case to first update your operating system sign.
Monal S: All right.
Sahed: Sure, sure.
Monal S: Do you know how to update it?
Sahed: Yeah, yeah.
Monal S: Alright, that is cool. You're from technical person, and…
Sahed: Yes?
Monal S: You already know these things, right? Okay. So, first, let's solve it. See, I'm not, running away from your query. I just want to solve it in, better. Yeah, okay? Fine, get it.
Monal S: If that solves it, then maybe the future software will not also create issue in your system, okay?
Sahed: Got it, yeah.
Sahed: Honor?
Monal S: Yeah, for sure. Yeah, thank you.
Sahed: I have shared already.
Sahed: Is it visible?
Monal S: Which… No, it is not visible.
Sahed: I think…
Monal S: See, I can try to solve it right now. I can try to solve it, but I'm not sure whether it is an issue with Windows itself, or the latest software. So, can we try once you upgrade the OS itself?
Sahed: Mmm, okay, then I can, by this week, I can upgrade, and if it is not work, then I think we can…
Monal S: In the week, yes, yes, we can connect again. But if you want to practice, okay, you want to practice, right? You want to start practice, can you go to Chrome and log into Google Colab?
Sahed: Okay.
Monal S: Google app.
Monal S: This is the best thing.
Sahed: Yeah, there I can, I think, yeah, I can do that there also.
Monal S: Yes, so for now, practice here, the same thing is there, but the issue currently is your VS Code and something is not matching. You can create a new notebook. Can you click on new notebook?
Monal S: Click on New Notebook at the bottom left.
Monal S: At the bottom left.
Sahed: Yeah.
Monal S: Okay? So, it will be saving into your Google Drive, so make sure to rename it.
Monal S: Maybe it will load, again, to the homepage.
Sahed: Oh, I think it is slow. Yeah, I can hear, here I can try.
Monal S: Yes. Rename the file when you, okay. Currently, the file name is Untitled0, okay? Rename whatever you like. Later, you can just export it when you are ready with your OS. Then we can again fix that issue, okay?
Sahed: Okay, okay.
Monal S: If you do import pandas, I think a lot of the things are already here, yeah? Explore this, this is very powerful. At some time, we will remove… we will not use our system.
Sahed: only.
Monal S: use Google Connect.
Sahed: But I think only that kernel setup and all, we no need to do here. Only remaining things I can do here.
Monal S: See, on the, on the, right side, top right, you will see Connect.
Monal S: Can you see, kind of.
Sahed: Okay, okay, okay, got it.
Monal S: Click on connect, and it will connect to the hosted kernel of Python.
Monal S: And your Python is active? Just, can you do import Pyth as PD here?
Monal S: Here, in the cell, yeah, import Pandas and PD.
Monal S: And do Shift plus Enter.
Monal S: or shift placenta.
Monal S: See? Pandas is all automatically installed here.
Sahed: Okay.
Monal S: And if you want your any files here, can you click on the files icon on the left side? There is one file icon.
Sahed: I can import.
Monal S: No, not here, not… no, no, not here, not here. Not here. On the right side, at the bottom right. At the… no, sorry, at the bottom left.
Sahed: Bottom left, yeah.
Monal S: Center, center left, sorry, I'm saying just words. Center left, there is one file icon.
Monal S: 2 icons below that, 3 icons below that, 3 icons below that.
Monal S: One icon below, one icon below. You can see this? Files, click on it.
Monal S: Here, you can upload your CSV and other files. You can copy the relative path, just like your, VS Code.
Monal S: You can add ExcelSX file, you can add a CSV file.
Monal S: And it will stay here, okay? Okay, okay, okay. When you are going to close this Chrome browser, your file is going to lost, but your notebook is going to stay in your Google Drive.
Monal S: Suppose you upload .csv here.
Monal S: Okay? csv is not going to present when you restart it, but your notebook that is on top, untitled 0.ip1bay file, is present in a Google Drive, all your coding will be saved.
Sahed: Okay, okay, okay.
Monal S: Okay? So for now, try this. It is very powerful, it is actually powerful than my system.
Monal S: Here, you can have access to GPU. So for now, let's try it, but update your OS first. Let's see what we can do. Okay?
Sahed: Sure. Okay, thank you.
Monal S: Sure.
Sahed: So, Windows 11 will work for me, then.
Monal S: Yeah, Windows 11 is the latest. That will work.
Sahed: Okay, I'll give it a try, and if not working, then I'll connect with you next week.
Monal S: Yes, sure, sure, sure. Yeah, thank you.
Sahed: Thank you.
Monal S: Nathan?
Monal S: You are next.
Nitin W: Yeah, hi Month.
Monal S: Anything, yes.
Nitin W: Yeah, I want to ask, see, I'm currently working in Java Spring Boot applications, and, I'm planning to ask for machine learning project in my company. So, how much, this, statistic knowledge is required for machine learning? I just want to check that.
Monal S: Machine learning is very statistics-based.
Monal S: It is heavy on statistics.
Monal S: Deep learning, I can say, you can skip statistics, but machine learning is required. But you can start machine learning, and if you don't understand something, then see.
Monal S: You want to ship machine learning in your company, right?
Nitin W: I agree.
Monal S: So, start with machine learning, ask ChatGPT, create models, have a basic understanding of what machine learning does, that is totally fine, because machine learning, there you will see distributions, outliers, these are all the concept of statistics. And I will suggest you to start few lectures of statistics, not complete all.
Monal S: Let me show you this.
Monal S: Okay.
Nitin W: It…
Monal S: And… Where is the Notion link? Not Notion link, sorry.
Monal S: Okay.
Monal S: You will see Batch 1, right?
Nitin W: Yes. Data science, you have access to that?
Nitin W: Yes, I have.
Monal S: Ultimate.
Monal S: Data, let's see.
Monal S: you have this batch one, right? And this batch one, if you see live sessions, there we will start with statistics.
Monal S: This is statistics 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5. There are a lot of statistics class, right? I will suggest to at least complete tail statistics score.
Monal S: Okay, see, this is the same day, this is not two hours, this video is separated into two parts, but at least complete the statistics 4, and then start machine learning.
Monal S: Okay?
Nitin W: Okay, okay, okay, yeah, welcome.
Monal S: product? Yes.
Nitin W: And, this machine learning…
Monal S: Complete this, as you can complete this scene. Krista has completed stats in 6 hours, just watch this.
Monal S: And then start machine learning, okay?
Nitin W: Yeah, this is a good act.
Monal S: 30?
Monal S: Sure. Okay, okay. That's okay. Thank you.
Nitin W: finance school, right?
Monal S: Happy you're doing well.
Monal S: Alright guys, done. Files get lost every time when you close? Yes, Rahul, it is session-based, but it is very powerful.
Monal S: Alright guys, thank you very much, guys, for joining today's session. See you next weekend.
Monal S: Until then, bye-bye. Bye, guys.
Monal S: Bye.